I will have you know that I finally got my coffee that I wanted to get yesterday and I don't know why I'm talking like this but I am.
I feel like it's appropriate.
Unfortunately the coffee is cold because I made it an hour ago and I forgot I had it.
I just noticed like five minutes ago oh yeah I have coffee.
It's you ever do that you make coffee you put it next to you and you go like okay time to do some work or whatever you know so you do whatever on the computer could totally forget you have the coffee ah man I could microwave it you know what I'll be right back it's a good idea
25 seconds should be fine today we're playing Doki Doki Literature Club yes you're correct that is what we're doing What are you doing today?
No, no, no.
We're playing Isaac.
Come on, I'm way too addicted.
But I will play that game at some point, I promise.
Oh, coffee's ready.
What a feeling.
Cheers.
Oh, perfect temperature.
Oh, yeah.
Last time was crazy, huh?
How sick was that?
Like, that run at the end last time was something else, you know?
Absolute insanity is right.
I can't stop thinking about it.
Like, that was so freakin' cool.
We gotta have more like that.
Whenever I get the data miner now, oh, you best know I'll be mining that data.
In fact, I'm mining all of yours' personal information right now.
I'm selling it to third parties.
I'm not.
You can have it, but I don't even know what I would use it for.
Okay.
I'm so ready for this, man.
Okay, let's get into it.
It's time for Isaac to make a stand once again.
Let's have a look at the to-do list.
Boom.
Go to angel-looking church area and dig on the X.
Check out ending 10 in stats menu and probably some other things.
Many things to do.
Let's turn it down just a bit.
There we go.
Let me also move this out of the way so I have room.
Perfect.
Look at that photo right there.
There's mom, there's me, and someone else on the left.
Ooh.
Who is it?
We're gonna figure out today, hopefully.
Also, I'm just now noticing that the bottom right part of the photo there, it's more bright than the rest, and I think it's because I... Actually, why is that?
Maybe I do need to go down all the way to the bottom and kill Satan as well.
I'm not sure.
The demon of the deep.
We'll figure it out.
Okay, so let me check here.
Last time, I think I checked until here-ish.
Let me just go from 10 and up.
I just want to see.
We're gonna look at some butts today.
Oh yeah, right.
Blue boy.
Someone in the comments called him Blue Baby.
Ending 11.
What was that one?
Wait, that's new.
Unless that is the It Lifts thingy.
Because at some point, now I'm starting to fight that instead.
Whoa, the audio on this one is way higher than the others.
Mastering is out of whack.
Right.
He has many facets.
It's all Isaac.
And that was ending 12.
Dude, we have ending 18?
What the hell did I do to get that?
So we went to ending 13.
All these we haven't gotten.
I got to see what 13 is and then we go to ending 18.
I want to see what that is.
Look at him taking notes.
Okay.
Now 18.
Oh yeah, that's where he turns around and becomes weird in the face.
No?
Oh yeah, it is.
It is.
That is fine.
He's gonna make a funny face.
So, 88 deaths.
Mom kills 14.
115 secrets.
2 is my best streak.
Let's see if we can break that today.
I'm gonna play So Patient today.
I am a changed man.
You know what?
I actually watched some of the crazy run back because I needed to experience it again.
Like, that was crazy.
I really regret that I didn't spend more time just looking at the items that I got, you know?
I was just too in the zone.
Today we're gonna take it slow.
Or we're gonna take it fast.
Because last time we did manage to overtake the timer on the loading screen.
So I wonder what that's gonna do if we keep that up, you know?
Maybe I'll do like slow specific runs and fast specific runs.
This is the one I tried to do last time with Lazarus and I failed miserably.
So maybe I'll try that again.
Also, I think I'm gonna make a new rule for myself.
And that rule is gonna be, if I lose with a character, I'm just gonna start another character.
I will never do the same character twice in a row.
Because I think it's a bad circle for me, you know?
It gets personal and I go like, okay, shit, we gotta go again, go again, go again, you know?
And then you start to play worse.
So if you keep it fresh all the time, I think it's a good way to circumvent that.
Or maybe just two runs per character, you know?
Something like that.
At least, don't go like ten runs in a row where we lose within the first five minutes because I get impatient, you know?
That's a bad idea.
Um...
Haha, this guy.
This fucking guy.
I mean, he is the most intriguing one so far, for sure.
And I really wanna try and... Obviously, I'm gonna try and win with all the characters.
I mean, that one's a given, right?
Obviously.
It's just a matter of time.
Um, Magdalene.
I guess I haven't played Magdalene in a while.
Or Cain.
Judas can go to hell.
But I will play with him again at some point.
But for now, he can go to hell.
Also, put it on hard.
Um, wait, I'm also just noticing.
Isaac has a heart on him.
Eden has a... Wait, what?
As Hazel has... I don't even know, crosses?
I guess it's like milestones, you know?
Like, okay, so I beat Mom or something with that character?
Probably, right?
Because on this guy, I didn't manage to do shit.
Same with that guy.
Yeah, I do remember having good runs on Cain, so it makes sense.
Let's do a... Dude, yes, let's do Eulith.
That was the character we used last time to get a crazy run.
But we're gonna do a normal run with Eulith now.
Oh, wait a minute, look at the little thing on Eulith here.
Because we beat Greed, right?
You see that little money symbol?
Ah.
We're going Eulith now.
Wait, did I put it on Greed?
No, I didn't.
Okay.
Let's see here now.
3.5 damage, we have this box of friends.
I'm not gonna give away my box of friends this time.
Even though it did pay off, in the end, it's not a good idea.
Oh, did he just walk into his own bomb?
Oh no, I walked into that now, that was bad.
You do diagonals, right?
You're a diagonal man?
Yeah.
Oh god.
He's immune to bombs.
No surprise there.
Dude, I'm actually at that point with this game where I can't stop thinking about it.
It's bad.
Like, I will be thinking about binding of Isaac, you know, when I'm sleeping.
When I'm brushing my teeth, when I'm pooping, it's binding of Isaac.
Nice.
Dude, so far, not a bad start.
Also, we have this weird symbol on the right with the arrows intertwining.
I'm not sure what that means.
It's definitely some kind of curse, right?
Or a debilitation that we have on the current floor.
The question is, what is it?
Let's figure that out.
Oh no, I can't get in there.
Okay, let me go down here.
Nice.
God, this song is so good.
It's perfect.
Get an item here.
What is that?
Let me guess, it is one of those things you put on a tit to extract milk.
The one's mothers use.
It's so fitting for this game, isn't it?
It's got to be.
Oh, glass cannon.
Be gentle.
Launches one large, high damage spectral tier.
Taking damage while holding this item breaks it, healing two full hearts of damage to Isaac, and granting the anemic effect for the current room.
Fully recharging the broken glass cannon restores it to its usable state.
What?
Taking damage while holding this.
Oh, that is scary.
Oh, it's actually we cannot.
We got to keep the box.
This is intriguing, but I'm not going to take it.
That comes later.
Oh God.
Avoid them.
Wow, they're fast.
Actually, masterful dodging there.
I'm impressed with myself.
We're going to duplicate our familiars here.
Big room, lots of enemies.
May as well do it.
I do want to do Lazarus as well today.
I need to try and beat it without losing a life so I can unlock that character.
I really want to unlock all the characters.
That guitar riff is banger.
Ooh, that was close.
Too close.
There you are.
Please be more bombs.
Okay, that's fine too.
I have three coins.
I could check out the shop.
And then we go to the boss.
Oh, I wish I could have gotten a bit more mana so I can use this box during the boss.
That was a miscalculation for sure.
I'm actually going to break this guy.
Oh, that was totally worth it.
Now, the question is, do I take this pill?
Or do I save up for the next shop?
You know what?
I'm going to save up for the next shop.
I'm not going to use my money willy-nilly anymore.
Cold and calculated money usage from now on.
We are going to lay down a budget.
We're going to calculate our expenses.
Everything is going to be taken care of.
No duplication for me though.
That's sad.
That was a good amount of damage there.
That was nice.
I didn't mean to do that.
That was actually really bad.
I think I should have pulled them towards the bottom and then went north.
Then, yeah.
Ooh, nice.
Very good.
Plus one luck.
Okay, and we don't have a devil room or angel room.
Move on.
So let's look at the devil stat now.
It's going to be a hundred percent.
A hundred percent.
And then something happens in this run that affects it.
We need to pay attention to what that is.
Like once and for all.
Oh god.
Kill those spiders first.
Still a hundred percent.
We have done nothing yet.
Uh, arcades so early?
Hmm.
I don't have that much money.
Maybe I'll come back to that.
I mean, I'll definitely come back to that.
Okay, we got to kill these guys.
This is awkward.
Good.
Get in here.
Oi, yo, yo.
Okay, get in there and kill it.
As long as it's not fully sized, it doesn't actually spawn any spiders.
This is the good news.
That was an awkward room to clear.
Broken remote.
Triggers to teleport affect each time an active item is used.
So the teleport effect...
I'm assuming it's referring to the other item that does the teleport.
The one that prioritizes rooms in a specific order.
I mean, we can do that, I guess.
Just kind of awkward because I activate my active to get more minions and then I instantly teleport away and lose them, right?
Maybe not the best idea.
Oh, oh god!
Oh, I was not ready for that.
That was fast.
First we take care of the walking dudes.
Beautiful.
Yeah, you know what, actually, I'm gonna...
Hmm.
Nah, it's okay.
What's that?
Three dollar bill!
Grants random... Oh, no, never mind.
I thought this was the one that gave me 99 coins.
Shit.
Grants random tier effects that cycle every six seconds.
I mean...
Okay.
Wait, does that even affect my... It does, okay.
It does affect my minion.
Still a hundred percent demon.
Oh, no.
Oh, my god, these rooms are killer.
That was a clutch petrified.
Wow, the lock on that.
Insanity.
Okay, we gotta eat the pills when they come up like this.
Experimental pill.
Wow, that's a massive range, that decreased.
That was like four in range.
But more tiers.
Let's see here.
This one is discounted.
Boom, I've never had it, apparently.
Even though I could have sworn I've had this before.
Piggy bank, three coins, spawns more coins when taking damage.
I'm really tempted to take this blue heart.
Blue heart and the boom.
But wait, the boom is gonna be an active, isn't it?
Which means I'm not gonna be using it.
Oh, I didn't... Oh, shit.
I accidentally donated.
That's fine.
I buy this and I come back, maybe.
Okay, we found the shop and the treasure room.
Maybe we do some stepping today, but we're gonna have the right setup for it, you know?
We gotta have healing, plenty of hearts, all that stuff.
Let's just go for the boss.
Ah, but if I... I need to remove this.
So I don't teleport away.
Okay, this guy's gonna shoot lasers?
Yep.
Oh, this is actually going pretty well.
Not bad at all.
And dog food, yes!
Huge.
Very huge.
Monster manual and missing page two.
This gives me a black heart.
Deals room-wide damage upon taking a hit.
That reduces I6 to one heart.
This will give up one red heart.
That's fine, actually.
I think this is good.
We get a black heart in return.
Ah, but is it worth it, though?
Necromancer.
I don't think I've ever had three in Necromancer.
Could be interesting.
I think I'm gonna go for it.
We gained more demon there and lost Angel.
And now we're at 33.8%.
That is suspiciously close to 33 point... well, like one third, right?
I think I just keep going.
No, no, no.
We're gonna clear everything.
This is the slow and meticulous run we're doing here.
So wait, I'm gaining stats every time I enter a room.
Oh, is that the... it's this one, isn't it?
Yeah.
The dollar bill.
Makes sense.
I'm gonna try and make a conscious effort to try and understand everything that's happening today.
Simply because last time I was so overwhelmed, I would love to just try and understand more, you know?
So every time I see something that doesn't make sense, we're gonna try and figure out why.
Very good.
Oh, this guy's gonna come jumping towards me.
Oh, that's a massive tear.
Look at that.
Too bad it's gonna be recycled here in a second.
Come on, jump at me.
You don't wanna...
Here, I'm here.
Nice.
These guys are super dangerous.
Good.
Come on.
Oh, that's a good tear effect.
No, stodging everything.
Dude, will you come over here?
It is so awkward to navigate these tight spaces when I can't shoot from my own character, you know?
Nice.
Now, any suspicious rocks.
No, but this is a floor decoration.
So is that.
I think, actually, maybe not the spiderwebs.
Because those have a functional effect, right?
They slow me down.
Maybe they don't count.
Oh, what the...
This is super awkward with these rocks.
Come on, kill him.
Yeah, kill the rocks, that's good for me.
Get rid of those stupid rocks.
Thank you, thank you.
Yeah, get the damage.
Nice.
Tough enemy.
Ooh, I like the bottom one, but what's this?
Let's Isaac throw a poison bomb, but that's an active, we don't want that.
Five percent chance when taking damage to destroy the trinket and spawn an item.
I do like that one.
Better than nothing.
I am gonna go in here.
Because we have a heart.
And I can also maybe donate a bit.
I do have two luck right now.
Yeah.
Wish me luck.
Good start.
Not good.
Don't worry, we'll make it back.
Everyone acquits right before winning big, right?
Ha, ha, ha!
Skatole!
Many fly enemies become less dangerous, I love that one.
We have poop on our head now.
And I'm gonna use a bomb as well here to blow up one of these.
Which one is it gonna be?
No, I'm gonna donate here first.
And we're gonna blow that up.
Amazing.
We're gonna save the last bomb.
So we found one secret room.
Man, I have a strong suspicion the other secret room is right here.
Like right here.
Watch.
Fuck!
Okay.
It was a gamble.
Sometimes gambling is part of the game, you know?
Oh God.
Scary.
You know what?
I could take a trip in there now.
I'm gonna lose HP.
Dude, that guy came back.
See that movement?
That was scary.
Okay.
Wait, we lost demon just now.
Hmm.
Why was that?
We lost 33% demon.
And now we gained it back.
Okay.
Maybe that's just how that works.
So now we have a question mark.
That means we're lost.
Oh shit.
I don't trust like that.
Dude, these guys have a lot of HP.
How are they not dying?
Oh, that's a nice tier effect.
It's very nice.
Shit.
I could do that.
But it's not gonna help me very much.
Oh.
Nails.
Oh, close one.
Come on now.
Solid.
Right, we have no map.
I came from the right.
North, there's nothing.
So this way.
This is gonna be a tough room.
Yeah, I don't know how I'm gonna survive this.
Okay.
Yo.
Ooh, wow.
That was rough.
Rosary bead.
The chance of encountering the Bible.
When a devil room would appear, an angel room appears instead.
You know what?
Let's try and go for the angel rooms.
Instead.
That sounds pretty cool.
I like it.
So we can go left or down.
Let's do... left first.
You are so annoying.
Okay.
Oh crap.
Okay, we managed.
I saw my life flash before my eyes there.
Oh no, these are gonna shoot the homing tears.
Oh no.
This is good, this is good.
I have homing tears too!
Stigmata.
Plus one health!
Yes, yes, yes.
That is incredible.
We needed that.
Like, every item that gives a plus health is at least a tier in my book.
If you imagine the classic tier list, you know?
Oh god.
I'm actually too scared.
Oh wow.
My range is super bad.
Ooh, oh, totally worth.
Check this out.
Beautiful.
He's gonna jump out?
Come on.
Yeah, there it is.
That could easily have gone really bad.
I'm glad it didn't.
Oh, I'm shooting teeth now.
Molars.
Come here.
I know you want to come here.
Stop hiding in the corner.
Lovely.
Let's check for doors.
And secrets.
I don't see any.
Oh, blow him up, blow him up.
Shit.
Oh, man.
Actually, let's blow this up instead.
Oh, that's satisfying.
So there's the boss.
I think I did already find a treasure room.
I did not find a shop yet.
I really want to go back and...
Oh, but I don't have any money.
And we have a full charge, so let's go in here.
It's the husk.
Oh, this is rough.
Wow.
That did more damage than I thought it would.
You kidding me?
That just saved me.
Hold on.
Um...
Damn!
That pretty much one shot the boss.
Massive.
Come here.
Do I go back though?
I think I do.
Man, not having a map is actually massively debilitating.
Because you can't really strategize very well when you can't get a good overview of where there's healing and other items, you know?
That you left behind.
So at one point, I gotta go south now.
Here.
You're gonna charge me?
Yeah.
Oh, man.
Good.
Come on, give me some nice...
Eternal hearts or something, that would be amazing.
Okay, a singular coin.
We'll have to do the trick.
I can't stand looking at this.
I gotta take it.
Even though it did nothing.
Whoa!
I'm so scared of these things!
Okay.
Well, that was worth it.
Wait.
Here?
Yeah.
So no shop, huh?
Unless I simply forgot about the shop.
It is possible.
Actually, let's grab that HP.
Oh, we also had one here.
So much healing.
We're getting out of dodge.
So this is the third now?
Fourth.
Oh, the timer is gone.
Interesting.
The timer is gone right now.
Wait, how much do we have?
We are at 22 minutes.
23 minutes.
I'm gonna try and pay attention to that.
Next time, we're gonna see when the timer disappears.
I wonder if they are so passive because of my Skatol.
That's it, right?
Also, let me just check here.
I am at one out of three on Necromancer and one out of three on both Beelzebub and Oakrap.
So let's keep those three in mind when we find new items.
Oh, this room is gonna suck with this character.
How am I... I need to duplicate here.
I don't know how I'm gonna do this.
Shit.
Fuck.
Okay, good.
But now there's two over here.
You know what?
I'm gonna...
How the hell do you do this?
What if I go here?
Oh, man.
We're gonna bomb him.
That's how you do it.
This is a brutal room.
Okay, I can't get across there.
This is the one that gives me randomized bomb effects.
I don't know if I want that.
I definitely do, because I get five bombs from it.
It's good.
Some healing would be nice, though.
Oh, no.
Fly enemies are better for me, though, so that's good.
Skatol is gonna help out.
Yeah, they're definitely more passive.
Look at that.
Guys, will you please just...
Come here, come here.
Running away from me.
Oh, that's huge.
Good.
Spawns one to six pickups.
All item pedestals draw from random item pools.
That sounds pretty damn cool.
I should try and save up for that.
This one is also pretty good.
Champion belt.
That's a solid amount of damage.
Oops, sorry.
I bumped the microphone.
Oh, crap.
Man, that is such a good item.
That does so much damage when it does trigger.
Just hide over here.
Kill a spider.
Okay, now we can focus on this guy.
Wait, the guy I have fallen... Is that a leech?
Where did I get the leech from?
Sketch hole.
Stigmata.
Wait.
Look, I have a leech following me.
I'm not sure where that came from.
Telescope lens.
Increases the chance of a planetarium spawning.
Planetariums can spawn in the womb and corpse?
That's an area?
Oh, God, now I want this instead.
But I need to figure out how I'm spawning this leech.
Grants random tier effects.
It's not that one.
It's not this one.
It could be this one.
Maybe it befriended a leech somehow, even though it's not really a fly.
Perhaps my character has an effect where when I reach a certain floor I gain a familiar?
Could be a thing?
Maybe?
Okay, let's go in here.
Duplicate.
Oh, fly enemies!
Oh, I'm happy.
Oh, this is great.
Sketch hole.
Wait, I'm spawning leeches now.
Another leech.
Yeah, it's definitely something innate with my character.
Caffeine pill spawns... Oh, okay.
Okay, X-lax.
Whoa, I almost slipped into the hole.
Let's not go there yet, because I really want to save up for chaos, if we can get it.
Probably not.
We're missing quite a bit of money.
But with some luck, perhaps, it's possible.
Envy.
This is an annoying guy.
Oh, the split shot.
I mean, the leeches are doing damage here.
Good shit!
I'm really digging Eulith.
That's cool.
I lost one leech, though.
Maybe when they die, they die.
And that's it.
Like, you spawned them at...
Ah, I'm not sure about that.
It's such a weird...
thing.
These guys are tanky AF.
Actually, scary.
That's right, the leech is killing them!
Amazing.
This is gonna be really annoying.
Oh, crazy attacks!
Look at that!
Good.
Whoa.
You bastard.
Oh my goodness, dude.
What an annoying room.
I gotta go back and heal.
Man, I need at least three hearts.
Like, two fields, borderline...
Like, that's dangerous, you know?
That's the scary territory.
Oh god.
Oh, that was beautiful.
I did more damage than I thought I would there.
At pill, we eat it.
Okay, well...
This is the anti...
Fuck, what is that?
Wego we pill, or whatever it's called.
Eat it, you get fat.
Oh, wait, can I get to that?
How do I...
I... no.
If I use a bomb here...
Maybe, actually.
Yeah, okay, okay.
Sick.
Liberty... No, I want to keep this... I want to see the frickin' planetarium thing.
These guys are not going to be scary, because I have the skidoodle...
Skidoodle...
Come on, man.
I need coins.
I need a lot of coins.
I need approximately 11 coins.
Plus minus zero.
Okay.
Oh, we're getting some resources, I guess.
Bombs can't become coins...
If we... Oh!
Oh, this room is going to be a nightmare.
Nice!
That's huge.
Oh, that's actually so beautiful.
We kind of nailed it.
Incredible.
Well, I think that's the end of this floor.
I hate to say it.
Would have loved to have gotten that chaos.
Here I cannot cross.
Or here.
Moving on.
Moving fast, actually.
This is the sixth level already.
No, fifth.
100% demon!
Okay, we got to write this down.
I feel like there's a pattern there.
A clear pattern.
Let me just write...
This just should be called...
Observations.
Floor two.
And five.
100% demon mode.
Okay.
Oh, man.
Lost my blue heart.
My precious blue heart.
My tear effect is messing with me.
That really confused me just now.
Oh, shit.
Wow.
Okay.
Well, we followed the rule.
We're not going to play that character again, then.
We're going to switch it up.
Let's do random.
I like random.
Oh, the spin.
And...
Fine.
Oh, at least we get this fast.
Big chubby.
Familia that charges slowly.
Yeah, okay.
And the direction on fire.
Yeah, that is very slow.
That is a slow charge.
Now, this character is, of course, famously impossible.
So we're going to, you know, try our best.
This bastard hit me.
Unbelievable.
Dude, I keep thinking I'm shooting with my familiar that's running around.
I need to unyule with my brain.
It's going to take a while.
Here's the poop.
I wish I didn't get a familiar.
It's messing with me.
We're going to drag them in a corner and go down like that.
That's the way to do it.
I wonder if I can get an eternal heart from a poop I spawn.
That would be nuts, wouldn't it?
We got a tinted rock here.
Good.
Huge.
I think my chubby also blocks attacks.
Because it's so big, you know?
Takes up a lot of room.
Uh, make a poop?
Yeah, coin.
I missed the room up here.
Still no bomb.
I wish to get a bomb so I can destroy that tinted rock.
It is a big wish of mine.
Oh, nearly missed that room.
These guys are going to speed up now?
Yeah.
Four coins.
Come on, give me another coin.
I can get this back.
Maybe there's a bomb inside?
I think it could be worth it.
Shit.
The Bible, though, is crazy.
Bible would go hard.
Okay.
Time to face the music.
Oh, these ones are tough.
I'm going to lose HP here.
We're going to wait here until they come close, and then we go down.
Oh, no, they're splitting up.
That's not good for me.
Dude, the charge was so fast, I couldn't even outrun it.
Charge me.
Oi, oi, oi.
Good, good.
Oh, not this item.
This is such a shit item.
Ah, wait a minute.
We can't get HP anyway, so maybe it is good.
I was about to say I wanted HP, but it doesn't work that way.
I mean, it does, but we get blue HP, and it's, you know, the most temporary of HPs that has ever HP'd.
Okay.
What is this room?
Good.
Make them small, but...
Dude, that just dropped two hearts, except it's useless for me, so crap.
Aw, I think it's already over, man.
One HP is rough.
You know what would be amazing?
This is what they should do.
They should take the black hearts and the way HP works on Azazel, and switch it with the blue boy the way it works.
That would balance things out amazingly, you know?
Have the blue boy be able to acquire more HP, and have Azazel be nerfed by having only blue hearts.
That would be perfect.
Literally perfect.
It's like very...
I mean, it's rough, you know?
Only being able to heal with blue hearts.
Nice!
I need more.
I'm gonna get a poop from this guy now, because I'm gonna be able to...
You know what?
Maybe the strategy is to stack up these blue flies, and try not to use them too much.
What's that?
It's a familiar that blocks enemy shots.
Okay, I mean, that's gonna help me.
Enemies will sometimes focus their attacks on it instead of Isaac.
This is good for me!
Survival above all else.
If I can't get survival in terms of HP, I can get it in terms of this guy, right?
Or in the form of this guy.
Oh, I almost ran into that.
That's unreal.
That is unreal, what just happened.
We're gonna do random.
Every time.
Like, that death felt horrible.
Oh, Eve!
That's the horror.
Eve is the horror.
Let me remind myself.
Nothing!
Two hearts, and she turns into a whore at some point.
When the goings get rough, we turn to whoring.
To whoring our body.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
I keep imagining someone listening in, you know, like, what the fuck is this guy playing?
What is that game he's always playing?
Holy moly, that's a lot of money.
Absolutely going inside here.
But wait a minute, this is ten.
Actually, this is the same amount as over here.
Before I open up this, let's see if we can find more bombs.
Oh, man.
Because I don't need to use the money yet.
I can wait, you know?
Let me take care of this guy.
Oh, he's gonna be pushed into the corner.
Let's see if we can get a couple coins here.
Dude, I'm tempted to buy this bomb.
Because that's essentially buying ten coins.
Or I guess five coins, it would be.
What I'm trying to say is we need bombs.
A lot of bombs.
Now, was there actually anything I wanted?
More options is pretty good.
So we can definitely probably get that.
I can get to twelve coins.
But then I need a bit more.
Let's go to the first floors down here.
Or first rooms.
Or we can scrounge up.
Uh oh, I'm at a corner.
I know you want to jump at me, come on.
You're aching to jump at me.
Shit.
What is that?
I don't recognize that.
Guys, come on.
Lil' Haunt, familiar that chases and damages enemies and sometimes applies fear.
So many familiars here in these runs.
Still only, man, we can get to thirteen coins, not fifteen.
Unless we step.
Come on, give me coins.
Coin me.
Ah, man.
We can step probably, is it once?
I think it takes one full heart to step.
But that is risky AF.
Like, I can't believe I'm just going to leave this room like this.
It is such a tragedy.
Actually, wait a sec.
If I put a bomb here, it should destroy these two and maybe also this bomb that...
Ooh, wait a sec now.
Check this out.
Not a word.
Wait, these guys are not normally here.
Yeah.
Nice.
Okay, this is going to be easy now.
Come on, Lil' Haunt.
Haunt this guy.
Spook him.
Dude, I just had a crazy urge to watch the movie Flubber.
You know that one?
The little green goop.
With, what's his name?
The comedian.
Okay, focus now.
We can't be losing HP here.
Okay.
Now, what's this?
Plus one damage and range?
Okay, sure.
I'm actually going to go back.
So, we have 14 coins now.
I could buy the bomb and...
Actually, yeah.
Dude, we just buy the bomb.
Right?
We buy... Yeah.
Buy the bomb, go back, grab the rest.
Bob's your uncle.
Why didn't I think of that?
Wait, there's... Oh, wait, alright.
For a second, I thought there were two 10 coins in there, but there's not.
This one.
We can even get more if we wanted to.
Uh, nah, we're going to save the rest.
And this floor has officially been cleared.
Great feeling.
Okay, so look at the timer.
Let me check the time.
The timer's here.
Wait, there's a question mark on my forehead for some reason.
Wait, why is that?
Oh, it's this one.
It's more options.
Got it.
Oh, I kept looking at my familiar just now.
I'm Ulithbrained still.
I need to un-ulith it.
Stat.
Look at my little ghost.
Go for it, buddy.
You can do it.
I'm having coffee right now.
Cheers.
Ah.
Feels good to just watch people work, doesn't it?
While you relax.
Thanks, little buddy.
See?
I'm going to call you Casper.
Come on, give me a...
a specialized heart here.
What's it called?
Eternal heart.
A lot of potential to get items in there with all this poop.
And there's a tinted rock.
I need bombs, though.
Oh, watch this.
Ah, shit.
Wait, there's a tinted rock here, too.
Should I gamble it to take this one as well?
Oh, sick.
I got three keys right now.
I'm going to use two of them.
Definitely worth it.
Look at all this.
The lovers is incredible.
And a pill.
This could be bad, but let's see.
Pheromones.
What does that do again?
Charms all enemies in the room.
Right.
Give me that one.
And we go back now.
We destroyed this thing.
Do we destroy this thing or the other one?
Ah, this one, right?
Okay.
Pretty damn good, huh?
Wait, I have another bomb.
I just got it.
Let's do it here.
Oh!
Okay, this start is phenomenal.
Let's not mess this up.
Focus.
Maximum focus.
The army's coming.
Holy moly, that's a lot.
My little haunt is doing so much work.
Come on, K.
Get in there.
This guy jumps very far.
I have my bird with me as well.
That's another thing that the whore has.
Forgot about that part.
The bird is so good.
Okay, 24 coins.
Voodoo head.
Spawns additional curse room on each new floor.
What is that?
So curse room?
I think curse rooms are the ones where you take damage through the doorway.
Improve the layouts and rewards within curse rooms.
Also causes one coin to spawn in each curse room.
I mean, with 24 coins, I think we take it, right?
No reason not to.
We're going to find more coins.
Yeah.
Now bombs though, that's another thing entirely.
Would love to get a couple more bombs here.
No more tinted rocks.
And again, I already found two in here.
I can't ask for more.
Oh, there's a freaking treasure room.
Should have gone in here first.
Oh, we can choose.
Oh, it's got to be that one, right?
Take one heart of self-damage to gain a tears up and deal 40 damage.
Subsequent uses in the same room cost half.
Consumes red hearts before other heart types.
It's an active.
No, we got to take this one, right?
I mean, just getting an extra heart is just goated in this game.
Although an argument could be made that the other one is maybe just as good.
If you use it right.
But I'm not going to use it right.
I made a tactical decision.
I thought it says sponsor Jack war.
Like, whoa, I've got a car.
I misread that.
We can go for that.
Come on.
All right.
Is it better than this?
Yeah, it is.
Emergency contact.
We may actually save that for mom.
It is just that good.
Oh, shit.
You got to be kidding me.
They damaged themselves with that.
Oh, supper.
Yes, sir.
We have so many red hearts now.
We're definitely going to take a deal here.
Too spooky for me.
Apply sphere to enemies in close.
That's a good one.
I have the occult is damage range.
Tears can be controlled in mid flight with the...
Wait, which one was that?
That sounds similar to the Ludovico technique.
But it's not quite the same, is it?
Tears can be controlled in mid flight.
I got to go for this.
Remind me?
Oh, oh, oh, oh, that's that's actually pretty cool.
I think I may take this too.
I know I'm being a little greedy right now.
But it's just going to amplify.
You know, it's just yeah.
I think it's good.
I mean, we only have one red heart.
This is pushing it.
It really is.
If we don't find more red hearts now.
We may be in trouble.
Okay, we gained a lot of damage just now.
Why is that?
Oh, wait, maybe it's because we have been we are now a whore.
Maybe that's what it is.
Oh, I have no keys.
Oh, shit.
I'm not going to do this yet, then.
I could get in there, but should I?
Yes.
Fuck.
Of course, that wouldn't work.
That was a major blunder.
What a blunder that was.
Insanity.
Let's hope we find some more bombs, huh?
To make up for that one.
Oh, it's not going to go down.
It's so weird that the tears stand still.
But it's also kind of cool.
I think that is a curse room.
Oh, I don't even have a key.
Oh, no.
Never mind.
Okay, what do we got?
My little unicorn invincibility.
I don't like that.
Continuum range.
Tears pass through walls and obstacles.
Wait, what do you mean walls?
Between rooms?
Tears that travel off the edge of the screen reappear at the...
Okay, okay.
Definitely.
Definitely that one.
I mean, that's...
That's pretty cool.
Oh, did you see that?
I can sort of...
Stack them up a little bit and then go...
New technique discovered.
That's massive.
Wait, I can go like this?
And then turn them left and right.
That is so funny.
Oh my god, I can shoot!
Of course I can shoot diagonally!
Like this.
Obviously.
Oh, that's sick.
Oh, man.
That just jumped the quality of this item for me.
By quite a bit.
Please be health up.
Yeah!
Wait, what?
Oh, okay.
We gotta go heal.
No healing, though.
Down here it is.
Uh-oh.
Don't you dare.
Huh?
Oh, I stepped on the friggin' thingy.
Whoopsie-doopsie.
Man, I'm lacking keys.
Shit.
I'm gonna try and get some HP or keys from this.
Wait, bomb is actually huge.
Come on, key me.
Not that the key's gonna be any good to me anymore.
If I don't have any money...
Shit.
We blow it up.
Actually worth.
Time for the boss.
This guy's kinda tough.
I may have to use emergency contact on him.
No, it didn't even hit him.
That's crazy.
Wait, I can also do this.
Hahaha.
Actually insane, look at this.
This is so weird.
Are you able to do this?
It is fun, though.
It is fun.
Okay, uh, give me that one.
Passion boy.
Okay, unfortunately just the shitty coins.
I don't think I like the pooping when I pick up the coins.
Actually, I do.
The farts thing is pretty good.
Or the poopy things on the floor.
Ah, we move on.
We keep moving.
Oh my god, sip.
Sixty-seven percent!
Uh, demon.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Um, what's the time?
Seventeen minutes?
I didn't pay attention to whether or not the timer was there.
Fuck.
Last time I looked it was twenty-two minutes and the timer was not there.
Hey, son.
Uh, this way.
Holy precision instrument, gamer.
By the name of me.
Oh, wow.
Diagonal shots are amazing.
That's fine, who needs it?
Not me.
I don't need that shit.
Interesting room.
Not interesting enough.
Dude, I love this technique with the...
The disco.
Wonderful.
Actually, that wasn't arcade.
Okay.
I could donate some HP.
Perhaps.
We'll see how much HP I get out of this.
Nice!
Good start.
I totally needed that.
The best fucking shell game ever!
A sane person would quit gambling now when they're ahead.
Never mind, I'm not sane.
We keep going.
One more.
For the road.
Unumas.
Lovely!
Take my HP.
Oh shit, we triggered the whore inside of us.
We have become horny.
Now we take this, and we keep going.
Give me all the money in the world.
Wait, if I... I wonder... I do wonder...
If I lose the last half red heart right now, am I gonna die?
Or will the blue hearts protect me?
I'm actually not sure.
I'm too scared to try.
Uh, child's heart, temps and increased chance of finding red hearts.
Uh, oh.
Yes?
Yes!
Me likey.
Now watch.
We're going back to the shell game.
We got another... Yes!
Oh, thanks.
Red heart me.
I like that my, uh, familiars are taking care of the enemies that spawn.
I don't have to deal with it.
Sick.
Gambling is amazing.
And I have zero in luck!
I'm starting to think luck has nothing to do with gambling in this game.
Then again, you'll never know, because it's all percentages.
I'd have to make a fucking spreadsheet.
Scat hole!
My beloved!
But we're not done gambling.
There's another gambling machine in here.
Keep gambling.
This is too much fun.
I'm probably not going to win anything here.
I'm being too greedy.
I pushed it too hard.
Huh?
Money, money, money, money, money!
Gambling pays off, kids!
I'm telling you.
If you gamble, it's good for you.
I do not give gambling advice.
This is purely entertainment purposes.
Get those spiders out of here.
Um, we gotta find a shop ASAP.
Where's the shop?
What the fuck is that?
Look at this guy!
That's a new one.
Never seen this before.
Oh, this is awkward the way I'm doing this.
It worked!
Uh, reduces, replaces all chests.
No, I don't want that actually.
I don't like that.
I don't like it.
I could actually get in here, but I don't want to.
Because I have infinite money.
Why would I?
Huh?
Rainbow effect!
Wait, nobody knows what happens when that happens.
That may actually be one of the biggest mysteries in the game so far.
That and the reason for why these fight rooms open and close, you know?
Oh, but you're flying!
You're afraid of me now, because I got scatole!
Don't pick it up.
Because I'm rich.
Nice.
Doesn't that rock look like a poop?
Oh wait, it's not dead.
Alright.
Uh, yes!
It's time to buy everything.
The dream catcher!
Yep.
Keys?
What's that?
Magic fingers?
Yep!
Bombs?
Why not?
I may actually save...
No, we're going to donate, obviously.
Donate.
As much as we can.
A red candle has appeared!
Alright.
Oh, it hasn't broken yet.
Okay, there we go.
It broke now.
So wait a sec.
This one consumes coins to damage all...
That is pretty good in my very, you know...
Special situation that I'm in right now, where I'm...
What do you call it?
Rich!
Let's try it.
Wow!
That was one coin worth of damage?
Holy shit!
Alright, this thing is bonkers.
Damn!
Incredible.
We got a sperm and a poop.
Explosions, damage, and concuss all enemies.
We got to try the new item.
Turdi...
It's E.
coli.
Touching enemies turns them into poop.
What?
Okay.
Oh crap, two out of three!
Let's see what other things we have going on.
We have Beelzebub and...
That's it.
Should I be doing other things?
There is a pill here somewhere.
I walked into the frickin' spike.
Oh wait, I'm walking the wrong way as well.
The pill is down here.
And there's also a chest, it seems.
That I missed.
Oh yeah!
I totally missed this!
Insanity.
Teleport to the secret room!
Huge.
Okay.
That one not so great.
More pills.
Don't mind if I do.
Balls of...
Yeah, that's good.
Gives me blue hearts.
Let's go to the secret room.
Alrighty.
I need more coins.
I don't have enough.
You may call this greedy, but I call it brave.
Wonderful.
See?
It paid off.
Okay.
Now we are about to...
Actually, I'm gonna go in here.
We have so much spare HP.
It's gotta be worth, right?
Krampus!
Hold on.
We're speeding.
Oh no.
This is a problem.
Oh shit.
Fucking use the coins.
Okay.
Went better than I thought.
Then we have the lump of coal.
Uh, yeah.
I mean, that's pretty good as well.
Yeah.
Makes it easier to hit enemies when I'm steering them around, right?
The music sounds pretty cool though in sped up mode.
Right?
Very nice.
Alright.
Now we're done.
Except let's check if this fight room is open now.
It ain't.
Wait!
Is it based on...
Oh, I think I know what it is.
I think I just figured it out, guys.
It's so simple.
It's based on the timer.
If we are ahead of the timer, they're open.
Huh?
Actually, wait.
Maybe that's not true, because sometimes I go into a room, I kill the enemies, and then the door opens.
So, you know what?
I take it back.
That's wrong.
What I just said makes no sense.
Given that observation.
Yeah, never mind.
Uh, we donated everything.
Time to leave.
It's a hollow.
I shall destroy you!
I'll beat a scene.
Uh oh.
Don't get pushed into a corner.
Wait, what am I doing?
I have spectral chairs.
Just shoot through the things.
Haha.
That's good.
We love this one.
More tiers is fantastic.
Uh...
Yeah, I was about to say we've already been in here.
Move on.
The next shop is going to be wild.
If indeed there are still shops.
Notice how the timer is gone now.
Timer is gone?
Oh, there you are.
It's getting a little bit confusing with these tiers.
Oh, fuck.
Oh my god.
Oh, they get feared when they get close to me.
It's saving my ass so much.
Oh, get away from me.
Stay the fuck away.
More cunny.
More cunny?
Did I say that?
More money.
Uh oh.
Oh, shit.
The stakes were made.
I want to get in here.
Fantastic.
That was a fantastic chest.
Now we still only have two red hearts, which is a massive problem for later.
So we shouldn't, you know, sell the skin before the bear is shot here.
We have to be on the lookout.
We gotta get more.
Oh god.
Nice.
Ooh, a massive...
That is a massive battery.
It's probably gonna give two full charges.
Oh, no.
What am I doing?
That was not good.
Oh, no.
That went better than I expected.
Magic...
Oh, that is a good one.
And then we have this guy.
Look at this.
This is a good one.
And then we have this guy.
Mmm.
I gotta take the mushroom, even though I don't know what this is.
I'm taking the mushroom.
For the sake of this run, I need to take the mushroom.
Because the mushroom is actually bonkers.
Sick.
This shop is my favorite place on Earth right now.
Fully recharges the held active item on pickup.
Eh.
What an underwhelming shop.
Holy shit.
Man, that shop sucks.
Justice.
What was that again?
Oh, wait, that spawns a beggar, right?
No, never mind.
That's not what that does.
Fuck.
Bomb him.
We gain demon.
Uh,
spawns a...
Ooh, why not?
They can do a bit of that.
And that's about it.
I'm gonna save the remaining money for gambling.
The battery pack sucks.
What a shitty and expensive item.
Wow.
Wait, I wonder.
Can I blow this up?
That's a massive discovery.
Holy shit!
Alright!
Wow, look at this chest!
Is that the best chest ever, or what?
Holy...
Oh, wait, that's my friend.
Uh, there you are.
What's hitting me?
Like, that chest was insane.
Unfortunately, I lost the soul heart.
Which is super valuable to me right now.
Oi, yoi, yoi.
Oh, what is this room?
Oh my god!
At least they're afraid of me.
You can't hit me.
Ha ha ha!
Oh, soul hearts everywhere!
Well, now I feel better.
A lot better, in fact.
Only certain enemies are afraid of me, I've noticed.
I think we go.
The gate!
I'm gonna throw money at his face.
Wait, maybe that was a bit too much money.
Spiders are scared of me.
Sick dodges.
That was beautiful.
That was frickin' beautiful!
I'm so proud of myself, that was fantastic.
More range?
I don't think I need that.
Let's see what our status is here.
One out of three on mother.
Oh crap, it's two out of three, fungi one.
Okay.
Good stuff.
I am actually gonna go back, I think.
I wanna go to the curse rooms.
Wish I had a shovel right now.
Shovel and some scotch tape.
Maybe some strips as well.
Oh!
What's that?
Gopi's head!
That's a new one!
Spawn to the f...
Wait, that's not new.
Haven't we had that before?
Hmm.
That's not new.
Liar.
The magic fingers, though, is a fantastic synergy with my coins.
But it's not that good.
It scales with tear damage.
I mean, this I can actually spam quite a bit, you know?
It's only one magic thingy.
Or a battery.
That's gonna go hard, I think.
If we can stack this up, you know?
I mean, I'm gaining the health back that I'm losing by entering these rooms.
So all in all.
Fantastic!
Look at all my flies.
Any more batteries?
There's actually batteries down here I can grab.
This is so optimization.
We gotta blow this up, too.
Just because.
And now we leave.
Wait, there's actually a pill!
Hold on now, we're not done.
I missed something.
Ow.
Okay.
You can... you can stay.
I don't really want that.
I have 16 range?
That is massive.
Okay.
Mom, I'm coming for you!
Because now it's mom time.
Oh, we get to see that it is a thingy and... well, mom.
The problem is with these dreams, I don't actually know what I'm looking at.
You know?
I will know later on when I know more about the game.
Fantastic.
I mean, I am just the sole man right now.
Or sole girl, whatever.
You know what I mean?
Oh, there's a room.
I also forgot my card.
Dude, this is starting to get pretty sick.
Oi!
Oh!
Oh, no!
Uh...
We need flying.
Or jumping.
We need something.
Is that... Mom's locket!
Heel for half a red heart whenever Isaac unlocks something.
Converts half a red heart, drops into whole red.
Oh!
Yeah!
I think I like that more.
Best friend!
That's what I saw in the dream, I think.
Places a decoy that draws enemies to it and explodes.
And metal plate.
Soul heart.
And chance to reflect enemy projectiles as a...
Oh!
That, I like more.
I like the current active I have, thank you.
The way I can just track them is crazy.
This is almost Ludovico.
But just almost.
Panic button.
So this one is a trinket, right?
It's not going to help me much.
I have to remember to activate my active much more.
Because it only has one charge.
And if I stay at range, I'm actually kind of stacking up my flies without using them.
Like, if I stay over here...
Ah, they're still going to charge in, I guess.
Inevitable.
Money equals power right now would be Chevskis.
Look at my range!
I think we definitely do gamble here.
Oh, that was a fly.
That's scary, because I don't have a lot of space here.
Wait, can we step here?
Maybe.
We got to explore the rest.
Because if we can step, I'm going to step.
We got to take a look around.
Oh my goodness.
Spawn more flies.
Maybe there's something down here.
Somewhere.
Uh oh.
Where are you?
Oh, there you are.
Follow me!
Ah.
I tried to look for a secret.
Thanks.
Ah, shit!
Right.
Come on, then.
Come on, I need to step.
There's no stepping!
Black hearts, though.
Maybe more blue hearts.
Yeah!
I think I take these first, and then the blue.
And now we're done.
I do wish I could get it and get that eternal heart there, but I can't.
Haven't seen any suspicious rocks, either.
I think I can't a little bit more.
Because at this point, I don't know what to spend my money on, you know?
Okay, just blow it up.
All right, that was good.
All right, Mom!
I'm ready for you!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Are you gonna step, Mom?
No stepping, okay.
This is gonna take me to two out of three on Fun Guy.
Good.
More healing.
Let's see what we get.
Shovel!
Wait, what was that?
What was that?
Someone's in here!
Oh, we got him.
Jesus.
Shovel or...
Money!
Oh!
Wait, we can have both!
Oh, yeah.
Wait, I can't go back?
No!
I saw...
Wait, this is a floor decoration.
Right?
That's a floor decoration right there!
Let's go.
Yes!
Wait, there's nothing in here.
Oh, wait, there's some...
I thought that was a fly!
Friend Zone!
Friendly fly.
Beelzebub, two out of three.
Orbital fly familiar that orbits at a medium distance and deals contact damage.
So this is basically one of the flies.
Party balloons!
No, it's my shots.
Like, if I...
That is so funny.
I thought legit balloons were falling like, whoa, you got a great item or something.
Is this so silly?
Cheers.
All right, Curse of the Maze.
I think that just rearranges some rooms from time to time, and that's pretty much it.
Nothing to worry about.
Oh, my God.
What is it with blue hearts?
This run.
I can't get enough of it.
Uh-huh.
Sure.
Oh, my God.
I really tried to dodge that.
Yeah, here comes the maze.
This is the maze part of it.
Come here, you.
Um, okay, I'm down here now.
Oh, okay, it just teleports me to a different part of the layout, I guess.
That's what this debuff does.
Like, the layout stays the same, but I can teleport it around kinda.
I can dig again.
Sick.
Uh, floor decorations, I don't see anything obvious here.
I think I see something there.
That's a floor decoration.
It wasn't?
What the hell, man?
Okay.
Fine.
I guess it's not a floor decoration.
Who's out here decorating these floors, though?
Ask yourself that question.
Like, someone's job, you know, is to come here and just lay down papers decorated with some bloodstains.
Interior decorator.
Uh, open up!
Thanks.
Don't shoot.
Don't shoot!
Okay.
I'm gonna hide in the corner.
That worked beautifully.
The coward's way is the way forward.
This room again.
Alright, mom, just keep moving, keep moving, keep moving.
Yep, there it is.
Uh, I'm excited.
Speeds up everything.
No, I don't like that one.
I don't like that it's sped up.
Makes me, uh, uncomfortable.
Ah, crap.
Okay, now we gotta look for a floor decoration.
Am I seeing any?
I'm not seeing shit.
Maybe this worm, but nah, not really.
Speaking of worms.
That's a giant worm, though.
That's gotta be a floor decoration.
Fuck!
Oh, what the?
Oh, it's my mirror image.
Albert, look at this.
Here's how we deal with him.
We charge up a couple like this.
Oh, he's dead, okay.
Never mind.
I was about to do something really smart.
Fight room?
Please be good.
No.
Nice.
We're not done.
Good.
Man, so many bombs in, uh, chests today.
Wow.
Can't believe it.
The chickens are slowly coming home to roaster, by the way.
I'm losing all my, uh, blue hearts here.
Maybe you cannot find, uh, these areas with items in this floor, you know?
Uh...
I'm gonna, well, I'm gonna stay, uh, hold on to my shovel, of course.
Let's just go.
Daddy Long Legs!
This is the guy I sometimes have with me.
He's a real bro.
Oh, I should have seen that shadow.
I'm blind.
Oh, careful, careful.
I
have terrible aim right now.
Oh, that was bad.
What am I doing, dude?
All my blue hearts are gone.
Thank God for the stem cell.
Love to see it.
Uh, very needed as well.
Uh, we're done here.
Moving on.
By the way, I'm probably gonna get the opportunity to do one of my tasks I have.
Which is...
Go to angel-looking church area and dig on the axe.
That's the one I wanna do.
We have a shovel now, baby.
Blow them up, blow them up.
Lovely.
Again?
This is so messed up the way these tears are working.
Oh, crap.
Oh, yeah, turn them into good poop.
Uh, this is a library.
Necromonicon deals instant damage to all enemies in the room.
Anarchist cookbook.
I mean, we picked them up to get the two out of three.
But I don't really like them that much.
Maybe I like this one a bit.
But...
I mean, I like the shovel more.
The shovel is gonna potentially catapult us into the stratosphere.
When it comes to finding secrets, right?
Oh, wait.
Okay.
I really wanna see this planetarium.
Oh, I was here.
Hide from them.
Oh, this guy's coming.
Oh, my goodness.
How did I not get hit there?
That was a minor miracle.
Get him.
Only three hearts, man.
Dude, I think I'm done.
I don't know how I'm gonna survive.
It's looking rough here.
Whoop.
Teleports to the... I mean, the shop doesn't exist here anyway.
Right?
Yeah, it doesn't exist on this floor.
It's not a real thing.
Oh, God.
That's a lot of worms.
Alright, that wasn't too bad.
Nailed it.
Destroy the poop.
Now, this...
Massive gambling time, please give me a million blue hearts.
Wait, what happened?
Did I just gain a fly?
Or did I get killed?
That helps.
That heart is for when I eventually fuck up and take damage on my way out of here.
Come on, faster.
I'm just gonna preemptively shoot here in case something spawns.
Come on, blue hearts.
Black hearts.
Come on.
I mean, bombs are kind of good, I guess.
They're gonna deal some good damage against bosses.
If I can remember to use them correctly.
Actually, against the heart, it's gonna be difficult.
Because there I want to stay at a distance.
Shit.
Okay, well, I can keep gambling, though.
Golden razor has appeared.
Oh, wait, that's like an invitation to Charlie's chocolate factory, right?
Puberty.
And unidentified.
Okay, well, whatever.
I think we're done here.
Strength, actually, clutch.
Oh, wait, whoa, I need the shovel.
Now we go.
Okay, wait, what if I dig inside here?
Nah, we're gonna try.
Oh, yeah, it lives.
It's a living heart now.
Heart is alive.
Oh, shit.
Wait, it's pulsing, that's funny.
Did it always do that?
I didn't mean to do that, I accidentally used my shovel.
I meant to use the other thing.
Shit.
I think we got it, though.
Yes, sir, there we go, baby!
We're going to heaven.
We're going up and away.
Take me!
Oh, not Curse of the Lost.
Please, anything but that, please.
No, not like this.
There's four ways to go, as well.
This is just not great.
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe, I was once a hoe.
We're going up here.
Oh, God.
I actually got hit by that.
Oh, whoa.
Okay, this is some next level.
I don't think my... yeah, this is...
I think this is the end of the road!
We gotta keep moving.
I don't know where they are, but they're...
Okay, he's jumping, he's jumping, he's jumping.
Dodge those.
He's jumping, he's jumping.
Good.
Deal the damage.
He's jumping.
Good.
The puke is coming.
Puke, puke, puke, puke, puke.
Focus.
He's dead, he's dead.
Thank God.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Not looking good.
Definitely getting in there.
Oh, wait!
Right!
We get healed when we get an upgrade or something, right?
Which one was that?
I need to see which one that is.
Touching enemies, turns them into poop.
Which one is that?
Oh, it's the locket!
Heal for one, yeah.
Oh, it's when I unlock something.
Nice.
Okay, well, that's pretty helpful.
Right.
Three hearts, though, against the final boss you have.
I have my doubts.
Look at these guys.
Spawning flames.
Oh, oh, this guy is buffing them.
Now he's over here.
Good, who's that?
Focus up.
They do be charging.
Oh, wait, wait.
We can dig somewhere.
We can probably dig here in this floor, right?
Floor decoration.
Oh, everything looks like a floor decoration.
Oh, wait, this one for sure.
What is that?
Touching bag, yeah.
That's gonna help.
Okay, we need more battery.
I wanna find more stuff like that.
Oh, god.
Where did you guys come from?
Huge.
Very good.
Holy moly, holy moly.
Oh, oh no.
Holy.
Man, I'm on edge.
Get ready for the jump.
Okay.
It's gonna jump any second.
There we go.
Oi, oi, oi.
Okay.
Oh, fuck.
I'm scared.
Come on.
Dude, we can maybe get blue hearts here.
Yes!
Huge.
Okay, we're gonna dig as well.
I saw a thing back here.
There.
Ha!
We can't dig on the heart floor.
The stone tiles.
Fuck!
No.
I didn't know that.
Shit.
Focus up, focus up.
These bastards are leaving flames everywhere and I don't like it.
There you are.
Okay, bomb.
We don't need that.
Fuck that crap.
I do wanna look for secrets, though.
But without a map, it's so hard to know where to put the bomb.
Nice.
Ooh, man.
Uh, wait, wait, wait.
I went up till I go left now.
Where are you?
There you are.
That was an easy room.
Actually, let's go bomb some stuff here.
Fuck yeah!
Ooh!
Ask again later.
You will die most likely.
You are dark inside.
Bring him the photo?
Wait, I feel like that's important.
Write it down.
The photo?
Are we talking about the, uh, the faded one?
Bring him the photo.
Oops.
Don't go to Discord.
Go to the game.
Thank you.
Uh, wait, wait, I could also...
Wait, it's changing here now.
What?!
The machine is gone!
Huh?
Unbelievable.
They changed it on me.
Kill him, kill him.
Play it safe.
There's a heart in there.
Um, do I...
Oh, I actually want this here.
Actually, hold on.
Maybe it's better if I, you know, clear one more room and then take the battery.
Because I can dig twice then.
What is this guy doing?
Come on, move.
Get out there and distract them.
Be the punching bag.
Oh my god, money.
I've gotten so much money in this run.
Okay, uh, should we try and dig here?
I feel like this is hard tiles.
But it's not the same hard tile as the other one.
So...
Wait, wait, wait.
I need to find the perfect spot to dig.
Where is...
Here.
Okay, battery.
Oh, there's only two...
Oh, okay.
Thank god, he died.
Oh no.
It's boss time.
Are we ready?
I think I'm just gonna go for it.
Like, this is it.
It's all or nothing now.
Wish me luck.
We got a lock in now.
Okay, come on.
No mistakes.
He's gonna throw lasers from the sky at some point.
Oh shit.
Yeah, here they come.
You got helpers?
Come
on, my punching bag.
Help me.
Come
on.
Not bad, eh?
I locked in.
That's amazing.
Eve's bird foot has appeared.
Oh, wait, really?
That's one of Eve's items.
We unlocked more of the...
Ah!
We need, I think, two more pieces in the top left.
No, wait, we have...
It looks like we have the center on the...
Maybe we only need one more piece, but then we need the dark areas filled out, too.
So, I'm not actually sure.
Because there's, like, dark areas and bright areas, right?
Okay.
We go again.
Random.
What's it gonna be?
Come on, please, it says...
Shit.
Eulith again?
That's fine.
I am a Eulith expert now.
I can handle anything.
Dude,
I love random.
We're gonna randomize every single run from now on.
It's great.
Alright, line up.
In an orderly line.
One at a time.
I know you all wanna get killed.
There we go.
Let's go this way first.
I need to Eulith my brain again now.
I need to get used to the fact that it's my familiar shooting.
At some point, I'll be able to, you know, switch between those two sides of my brain fast enough.
But it's gonna take a little bit to get used to here again.
Good.
Solid.
Why not?
Let's just go for it.
We haven't found treasure room yet, but we're gonna go back and get it, of course.
Nice.
No problem at all.
No problem.
Clean.
Damage and range.
Fantastic.
Not leaving yet, of course.
I wonder what character would be the best to do a lot of steps on.
If we're gonna do 10,000 steps a day, maybe we need a character that is just like the tank, you know?
Something like that.
Actually, it's gotta be the one that heals with the yum heart, right?
That would be the way to do it.
Except that does require battery, I guess, but...
Uh, Explosivo?
A chance to fire a Sticky Two that will grow and ex... Oh, that one.
Uh, yeah, why not?
It's a little dangerous, but...
Net positive, I would say.
Oh, look at this!
Uh-huh.
Photo!
Wait.
Dude, wait a minute, is that the left half of that photo?
Look, there's a little kid on the right.
Or in the center, right?
Bring him the photo!
Who?
Isaac?
Satan?
I don't think Mom is a he.
We're gonna bring him the photo.
We cannot lose.
Yes, pill me.
Fantastic.
Wait, oh, I was hoping it was the other one!
I was gonna glitch the shit out of this game, but...
it unfortunately isn't.
Wait, what would this one do again?
Can break rocks and damage enemies...
That one is actually pretty good, but oh, it's inactive!
We cannot exchange the one we have.
The one we have right now is simply too good.
It is out of the question.
And we're not actually... we could go in here and just look.
Yeah, stuff like this, right?
I should always do that.
Maybe there's a coin here.
Okay, there isn't.
But that could be.
Dude, I'm actually so excited about the photo thing.
Bring him the photo, and then we get the photo right after.
Like, it's gotta be... like, some kind of secret, right?
And look, we have the timer.
We're gonna try and keep track of it this time.
Remember, at 22 minutes, we saw that it was gone.
100% demon mode, again, on floor two, every time.
Oh, the bomb is so good there!
That was a red bomb.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, dear lord.
Those bombs scared me.
Goodnight.
Cancer.
And, oh, the freezer baby.
Yeah, wait!
Yeah, it works with my shots!
Oh, that makes it so good!
Love that.
Oh, careful with the bomb.
Dude, when I duplicate this, am I gonna duplicate the freezer as well?
Surely, right?
I'm not gonna do it yet, but when I do, I'll try and see.
It's not something you can miss.
Yeah, blow up the ice so we can...
exactly.
Go get it out of here!
Oh, fuck you.
Hmm, how am I gonna do this?
Maybe if I run fast.
Yeah, that's the way to do it.
Wonderful.
I'm a little bit afraid of the bombs, though, that I put on the enemies.
I should not have used my key there.
That was so dumb.
Oh, well.
We have a Bible.
No money, though?
Oh, God.
Wow.
You know what?
Why not?
Let's do it.
I can duplicate.
Oh my God, we got... yes!
Look at that damage.
That's crazy.
Look at the knockback!
I can't even reach me, dude.
That's crazy.
Breeze's fire rate?
Oh, man.
Yes.
Uh, do I... do this, though?
Necromon...
Oh, that's not the one I...
No, I didn't mean to take it!
I didn't mean to run into it!
Fuck!
Well, that's a rip.
That's a fucking rip right there.
Shit!
I can't get past it?
I thought for sure I could get past that without actually touching it.
Well, this just got a lot worse.
That one red heart was my lifeline.
And that's gone now.
This is suddenly very bad.
We need to lock in now.
No mistakes.
Until we get a red heart.
In fact, I wonder what happens if I find a pill that would give me one health down when I don't have any red hearts.
That's curious, isn't it?
That's an interesting experiment.
33 demon?
And pill?
Come on!
Oh, am I gonna waste a bomb on that?
Not yet, not yet.
I may do it soon.
This looks a little scary, actually.
Freeze him!
Oh, the bomb, yeah!
We even opened the door to this chest.
Or made a path, I mean.
Oh, what?
Oh, no, I stepped on a fucking...
Oh, man, it's actually over!
No!
Such a promising run.
Okay, we got a pill.
That's not what I need right now.
Okay, all our hopes and dreams are contained within this random pill down here that I'm gonna get now.
Everything relies on this.
This... is it.
Wish me luck.
There's two pills!
Ex-lax, all right, come on.
Be good to me.
Dammit!
Fuck!
Okay, we gotta go in here.
Get frozen, nerd.
Well, we gotta buy the blue heart.
That is non-negotiable, I think.
But that one is also interesting, I don't know what it is.
Donate one.
This run is over.
Get rid of my money.
Let's not make any stupid mistakes like walking into a...
Oh, Jesus, fuck me!
Dude, this is crazy!
Oh, it's because they sped up, I understand.
Fuck, I was like, why are they shooting so fast?
Nah, man.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
And there's the... there's the boss.
I think we're just gonna go for it.
Wish me luck, this is it.
Lock in.
We duplicate and we go crazy.
We're too close!
Holy shit.
Huge!
Give me HP.
Yeah!
Stem cell me.
I'm scared of these rooms now.
Ho... wait.
Can I become twice the whore?
That I already was?
Not that I want to take anything in here.
Absolutely not.
I say no to all of that.
No way.
It ain't happening, bro.
I just can't risk it, man.
My only hope is to get high on pills.
This is how we win this.
Shit!
Well, that black heart was destined to go, you know?
I'm just glad it happened now.
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
Don't touch him.
Okay, well...
Oh, you're stuck over there.
That's too bad.
Oh, god!
HP me!
We actually have some HP.
What's that?
Odd mushroom.
Less damage.
Damage down multiplier?
Ugh, I mean...
Okay, hold on.
Actually, getting more tears is massive when I have the effect of freezing, right?
I like it.
I think this is a good choice.
Like, look how fast I'm shooting up.
That is crazy.
Fire rate is off the charts.
Now we grab this.
And we leave.
It's time to get out of here.
And then we gotta find some...
Oh, hold on.
Alright.
We gotta find some more hearts, because this is looking very grim.
And there's no dawn.
Guys, it is always darkest right before dawn, right?
I can use two keys here.
Am I naughty enough?
I am.
Holy...
Wow.
Now, do I gamble on myself?
That I can win this, or do I donate everything?
Oh, choices.
Do I believe in myself?
I'm gonna give it some.
I'm gonna give it till 20.
That way I can get a 15 item and a 5 item if there's a heart.
He's gonna blow up, he's gonna blow up.
Yeah.
Blue heart, huge.
So now we have one red heart, one blue heart.
Keep track of it.
Wait, my little guy's not shooting faster.
No, my freezer man is shooting normally.
Look!
It's unaffected.
That's a freak.
Wait a minute.
For science.
Oh my god!
Shit!
Oh well.
Oh god, kill him.
That is so huge!
The blue hearts are saving me right now.
How is this real life?
I need a shop stat, because I got money to spend.
They're burning a hole in my pants pocket.
Oh no!
Stuck in the car!
I don't know how much HP I have.
I think I have one red, one blue.
Jesus Christ, give me luck.
Oh man, more mushrooms?
No.
I don't want that.
I want pills.
This room is going to kill me.
Okay, we somehow survived.
Fuck these guys!
There's a fucking hair in my mouth.
I got one bomb.
Duplicate!
There's no one surviving this.
And fornicate.
Jesus.
Oh!
Kill him.
The scariest thing is, I don't know how much HP I have.
Okay.
Layout, got it.
No.
Not like this, not like this.
No!
Okay, you motherfucker.
Die!
Oh, I'm so low HP probably.
Kill him!
Get away from that.
Shop.
No, wait, that's not a shop.
Fuck.
Okay, it's still good though.
What is that?
Looks like a familiar...
little low-key four-way buddy.
Familiar that fires tears like...
Does that work with me?
Oh, it does.
Okay, cool.
Well, it's not gonna matter if I can...
No!
Not this!
I hate these enemies so much.
The hardest enemy in the game.
It's not even close.
It is such a bullshit enemy.
I hate it.
Random, random.
Come on, Sazle.
Sazle!
I know you got it.
Not Judas!
Get out of here.
Oh, wait.
Yeah, okay.
Come on.
Oh, oh, oh!
Look at this!
I need bombs.
Why do I always see those things when I don't have bombs?
Isn't that kind of funny, the way that works?
We got a treasure room here, though.
That's huge.
Come on now.
Okay.
Lost contact.
They collide with and destroy enemy shots.
That's pretty cool, I guess.
Didn't really want to spend my money there.
Wait, am I...
Okay, these tiers are actually kind of dope.
I forgot how big they get.
This was a great upgrade.
Hey-o.
Come on.
Now we got a bomb.
We're going back.
Actually, we had one already, it seems.
Ooh, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on now.
Okay, I'm definitely getting in there, too.
But first, we put it strategically here in case there's a secret door, too, you know?
Okay, that's big.
And then we destroy...
Oh, we do it right here, dude, so we get two for one.
Perfect placement.
No words.
Not a word.
We can do it again.
Huge!
We're back on top.
Do I go for the last...
Dude, this pillar's going to be plus one HP.
I feel it in my bones.
Shit.
Wait, what is this room?
Look at this!
Why does it look like that?
Interesting.
No doubt, satanic rituals are happening in there.
I want to put an end to it.
Oh, man, what a...
What's that?
A used diaper!
A chance to gain the scatole effect for the room.
Spawn a blue fly...
Oh, I mean...
Cool.
That's disgusting.
That's just nasty right there.
Don't get hit by the laser.
I'm getting good at not getting hit by the laser.
Except I kind of fucked myself there.
The creep is still there!
Okay.
Damage and range up.
Wait.
Oh, wait, I see that.
Hold on.
Only apply to shots fired from the right eye.
Oh, yeah.
One of them is also slower than the other.
I wonder if the increase in range...
That goes to there.
That goes further.
So, I guess it's like the way it's calculated is there's a certain distance they go.
And a certain time they need to get there.
I was about...
No, that would mean that the longer range ones would move faster.
But that's not the case.
That's not what I'm seeing.
Okay, I don't know then.
But range somehow affects the shot speed, I guess.
Have we been to a treasure room?
I just don't remember.
Let's make sure.
That was a shop.
Okay, we have.
Get out of here then.
Off we go.
Okay, 100% demon mode.
Arcade, huh?
I do have money, but I'm gonna save it for the shop.
Thanks for making a little entrance for me.
Crap.
Oh, that was so lucky.
Now we have enough for the shop.
Yeah.
Promising.
Okay.
No bombs though, so that's a bummer.
There's a shop.
Be still, my heart.
Mom's foot, okay.
Notched axe.
Oh, but wait, I don't want to replace my current one.
My current one is pretty good.
Do I want to replace it?
Let me see here.
Can break rocks and damage enemies, limited users per floor.
Maybe I will.
Okay, this one's gonna save everything.
Nice, and then we take this.
Nice.
Let's see here.
Oh no, I need more money.
Endless, nameless.
Chance to spawn a copy of a card pillow rune.
Okay, that's not too exciting.
Honestly, these are not that exciting.
I'm fine.
I'm good.
Yep.
If I get seven more coins, I'll come back and maybe grab that so we can try it on this floor at least.
The toenail?
I didn't get to read it.
They're in combat dropping.
Oh no, this one is terrible.
Oh, I want to get in there.
That's what we need the pickaxe for.
We got to break this rock.
Okay, let's come back when we have seven.
Shit.
Yeah, pickaxe sounds pretty good right now.
Infested.
Destroys all poops in the room and spawns a friendly spider for each.
Cool.
What a perfect room to get that in, huh?
Do we go yet?
Yeah, why not?
Larry!
That's a lot of Larry's.
Actually, I'm going to get more damage.
I'm stuck in a court.
I'm going to get fucked here.
One percent.
Okay.
Tropicamide.
Tear size.
Good.
I need to heal though.
Oh, Judas is rough with one HP.
Like, what do you even do if you don't get health up, you know?
Let's go this way.
Oh shit!
Oh, if I pushed that into the rock, I didn't have enough time to react to that.
Oh wait, I shouldn't have gone in here actually.
Not yet.
I need this.
That was unnecessarily risky.
Wait, what?
Oh.
Nice.
Oh, this one.
Oh no, that's going to kill me, isn't it?
We can't take it.
I actually can't take it.
It will kill me.
Ah, but we got to take it.
We're already so risky with one HP.
We got to go with it.
May as well go all in on the risk at this point.
Wait, there's actually a card I want to grab before I leave.
Oh yeah, this one, right.
One thing I'm curious about though, so the bombs, they're not going to destroy it.
It's only an enemy hit, right?
To fire a Sticky Tier that will grow?
No?
Yeah, when it's attached to an enemy, okay.
But maybe there's a chance?
You never know if the description is incomplete, you know?
Wait, it doesn't even spawn a bomb?
But how will it know?
Maybe it says, okay, check if there's enemies in the room.
If there are, then there's a chance to even display the bomb effect.
We are leaving.
Why am I green?
I have the flu or something.
My tears are so slow, I need the shot speed.
I'm drowsy, oh no.
Actually, that's good for me, isn't it?
Unless it means, no, it's only me who slow down, right?
It's not everyone else.
We're going to wait a bit.
Okay, that resets it.
Close one.
Should I go for this one?
Yeah, I think so.
Key is actually massive.
That's right, enjoy the bomb.
Wait, again?
Okay.
It means I have an extra.
Oh no.
Fuck.
I'm going to die, I don't know how to do this.
Wait, maybe I need to.
I have an idea.
Holy shit.
Nice.
Nice, nice, nice.
Oh man, oh man.
I need to bait one of them at a time.
Holy.
I know you want to jump to me.
Imagine if you jumped into me with the bomb and killed me.
This is what I was afraid of.
I know you want to come here.
Horrible item.
What is this?
That's terrible.
My plane is so safe, I'm not going to risk taking damage here.
Like, I'm already thinking, if I don't find HP up, like, I'm not going to be able to do any of the late game stuff.
Like, it's just out of the question.
Who's shooting?
Oh god.
No!
I can't hit him!
This is insane.
Dude.
Unbelievable!
We got to go back and heal.
Ah, that's a waste of a heal there.
Phew.
Wait, I have no keys, but I also have no money, so whatever.
Uh-oh.
Uhhh...
Okay, not too bad.
Okay, this one should be easy.
We just go around in a circle.
Dude, I feel like the item that makes me absorb their bullets actually works against me here.
Like, I shoot so slow that I never get a hit in, you know?
Like, it's super rare.
Oh, the bomb would've been big.
Fuck, Judas is painful.
I don't even have bombs.
No.
Go in here.
Ahh...
I mean, if I'm fast enough, I could potentially walk in there, take half a heart, go back and heal.
Ah, wait, I don't have no key anyway, so what am I saying?
Let's go for Gertie.
That almost was a really bad decision I just made.
Oh, he just dies from that!
Mom!
You're kinda nuts.
Oh, that's huge.
The breakfast is clutch.
Let me just go window shopping.
I'm definitely not getting anything in here.
Fuck.
I need that.
I shouldn't even have gotten in.
Now I know what I'm missing.
Fuck.
That is action.
That is...
Hold on a minute.
What was the other one?
Oh, wait, it's over anyway.
You know what?
Good for me.
I shouldn't take anything.
We stay at 2 HP.
Let's take the win.
Let's pretend we never saw that.
We didn't even get a Devil Room, guys.
It didn't happen.
We got unlucky.
Yeah.
We got an extra heart.
We're rolling.
Fuck yeah.
We did not see what we just saw, because it didn't exist.
It's not real.
It's insane what one extra heart can do for your self-esteem here.
Like, I feel like I have infinite health now.
Huge key.
What?
Whoa!
Hello?
Look at these black shits.
Let's make it really dark in here.
That's weird.
RuneShart, Uyghur effect.
RuneShart.
Why doesn't it tell me what I get, though?
It creates a trap door.
Okay, we definitely got to use that somewhere.
Two red hearts.
I guess we'll make them over here.
Like, more?
Dude, we can totally step.
Actual stepping?
New item.
Oh!
Wow.
Alright.
Not bad.
Huge.
I'm actually gonna heal.
Reveals.
Nice.
And this one is Harkalas.
That could actually come in handy.
I'm gonna go look for...
floor decorations.
I'm not convinced by any of these yet.
Dude, the homing shots!
This grass looks like a floor decoration.
But I'm not sure if it is.
Okay, so they shoot like that.
Aww, are you kidding me?
I'm at a Lagrangian point here.
This way.
Okay, we can definitely destroy that.
Nice.
I don't know what qualifies.
Dude, the homing shots are crazy!
They bend a lot!
There is no spoon.
Let me go back to where I came from and look for obvious floor decorations.
None of this is obvious to me.
Should I... Okay, I'm gonna try the grass.
I feel like... Okay, there's grass everywhere.
This one is... You see this blue stuff here?
No, no.
We're gonna save it.
I'm not 100% convinced.
The bomb is good.
Okay, let's see here.
Okay, this floor decoration is actually glimmering.
That's gotta be it, right?
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Huh?
Yeah!
Okay!
Nice!
Uh-oh.
What's that?
It's a new one!
D4.
Re-roll into something else.
Re-rolls each item currently held into a different item from this...
What?!
On a... Whoa!
Uh...
I feel like I should not do it, because I have pretty good items, man.
Like, I... Also, if I re-roll breakfast, will I lose a HP?
Uh... I'm not gonna do it.
This seems too fucking risky for me.
Like, this is my one shot, you know, to actually get Judas and do something with him.
We can't waste it.
It's basically like a mobile version of the dice room, you know?
Speaking of, I haven't seen those rooms in ten years.
Like, where did those go?
Uh... Also, I wanted to go back to that room with all the runes.
There was another rune on the floor that I didn't grab.
Dude, we need to step.
Hargelas, right.
That could maybe come in handy.
I think we had some rocks I needed destroying somewhere.
I think right down here, actually.
This one.
Uh... We're gonna wait, though.
Maybe there's a better room for this.
I'm scared of those little spiky boys.
Don't do it.
Okay.
Get bombed.
Dude, they're homing tears!
It's one of my favorite items now.
I love it.
It is so good.
Especially when you have shit aim like me.
Okay, I like that.
We're gonna run with that until we see a room where we need to destroy things.
No fucking... Ancient Recall?
Nice.
Hold on.
Uh...
What's up with this?
Dude, I kind of wanted to... Oh, man, I should have done digging in here.
40 damage.
Let's see what else we have.
The shop?
Oh, that's right there.
That's useless.
French flight!
And this one is strength.
I'll keep this one for now.
Diplopia duplicates all pickups and item pedestals.
Mmm...
That is pretty good.
Wait a minute.
Passably increases devil.
I have 6% though!
Like, it's not doing a good job of it.
I think I'm gonna replace this.
I already got the book effect, right?
So we're fine on that front.
Wait, uh...
I'm confused.
Why is there a ladder here?
Charge shot that fires up to five tiers in a burst.
Taking damage mid-charge teleports Isaac to a random room.
That sounds horrible.
We can buy a black heart!
Monkey paw spawns a black heart when Isaac is reduced to a half a heart.
It's consumed after three times.
Um...
See, I don't know why this was open per default up here.
Maybe it's like open for the rest of the run now or something.
Hmm, I need to read this thing again.
I need to understand exactly what's happening.
It's all pickups and item pedestals.
So pedestals are this one, right?
That's a pedestal right there.
And item pickups...
I think it counts as everything.
So if I do it here, I get double the cards, right?
For example.
I'll be back.
Look how much it bends!
Like, I thought it was just going to be a slight variation in trajectory, but this is...
crazy.
Light save.
There's a room I'm missing.
Oh wait, I think I know what it is now.
It's that one, right?
All shops contain a trap door to an exclusive?
Yeah.
The special shop sells items and pickups not normally found.
That's the one.
Uh...
You know what, maybe I start... it's time to use some of these cards.
Like flying or destroying rocks.
I have only one bomb.
Yeah, let's just do that.
We'll be using flight.
Maybe it's a waste, I don't know.
Wait, that's not the one.
That's the one.
Which chest do I want?
Red chest or the other one?
I think the other one is better.
Yeah, the red chest sometimes contains spiders, right?
We don't like that.
Decent, I guess.
I could bomb this.
What I could do, though, is go to this room over here...
Oh wait, I should have brought one of these cards with me that produced hearts.
It's okay.
Ah, I don't want... no, no, I can't waste my blue hearts on that.
I know I'm being very indecisive right now.
But I find myself in a very good run here with Judas.
It doesn't happen every day.
I got to play strategic.
Give me that one.
Just use it here, honestly.
May as well use the cards before we go on, right?
And this one was what?
The hermits?
Okay.
Let's go!
Vistula!
Oh.
Yeah, Bend!
Bend, my little buddies.
Pentagram!
Oh, that's a lot of extra damage!
Huge!
That is massive.
I got seven damage right now.
I am blasting!
Also, I'm noticing on the map that the secret rooms, one of them is a bright white color, and the other is a sort of gray.
Just interesting, isn't it?
Okay.
Depths one.
Oh, shit.
Whoa!
Close one.
What's that?
Brown cap, poop explodes?
Nah.
Not interested in that.
What?
Oh, he jumped, he jumped.
Makes sense.
I do have a lot of keys, so why not?
Ringworm!
More tears, spectral tears, tears traveling.
Wait, wait, wait.
This may be it.
Okay, actually, I love it.
Also, that doesn't seem random at all.
That seems very consistent.
What do you mean random?
Maybe it changes when there's enemies?
I mean, they're gonna...
They're gonna be homing, right?
Okay, now it's random.
Oh, this is actually kind of a mess.
But a beautiful mess.
This may be a bad idea.
But I mean, they're spectral.
We could just hide on the other side of these rocks.
It's great.
And when they find something to stick to, it's bombing time, you know?
Oh, thanks for that.
Clicker?
Transform the current character into...
What?!
Activating has a 50% chance to remove the most recently collected...
SASIL!
Shit.
Did I lose something?
I may have lost something.
I like it.
No, we're gonna... we're gonna transform again.
That's right.
And then we're gonna...
If we find pickups, we're gonna come back for the Diplopia.
That's right, baby.
We're gonna transform everything.
Shit.
Okay, I'm starting to dislike this ringworm.
It's not pleasing me.
I'm not gonna fucking...
Where am I stuck?!
Oh, there was a fucking hole!
I didn't see that.
Well, this is going downhill.
That was horrible.
I was like, I can't move!
Alright, dude.
Say goodnight.
Okay, yeah.
This ringworm needs to go out.
I hate it.
Ringworm sucks ass.
Sure, take that instead.
Although I would want the other one I had, ideally.
They're jumping?
Just bait them into me.
Come on.
Dude, there's a lot of enemies in this room!
That was quite the room!
I don't even have healing.
Oh, no!
I gotta go all the way back.
Gotta play it safe.
And then I'm gonna change my trinket back to the other one I have.
What did that do, anyway?
Oh, yeah, that's a total effect.
That's decent, I guess.
But only a chance for that to happen.
Yoink!
Well, we're actually just back to the...
What did I call it?
The Judas Experience, now.
This is the standard Judas Experience with a different haircut.
That's what this is.
And an extra life.
Look at that!
I was about to make a reference to that movie where they bent bullets, you know what I mean?
The one with Angelina Jolie.
Charles Hart?
Oh, no, not the jumping jacks.
No!
Bomb them!
Oh, no.
There's more coming in.
Oh, shit!
I didn't mean to do that!
Oh, this is not going well!
No, I misclicked it, dude!
I misclicked it.
I misclicked that button.
That's unfortunate.
What a fucking throw there.
Well, you know what?
Fuck Judas anyway.
That was destined to go bad from the moment I got the character.
NOT AGAIN!
What is it with these two?
Not again!
What's that?
Nah, it's not that good.
Actually...
This is actually kinda good.
I take it back.
It's decent.
Come on, dude.
We have to remember to poop here.
Pooping is an integral part of Blue Boy.
Oh, massive!
What a start!
That's nice.
These back, yeah, they're these back, okay.
Oh my god!
Huge!
Bless me with a shot now.
Well, we're taking this, obviously.
Any time we get an opportunity to get a Blue Heart, we take it.
We keep the rest of the money.
Dude, these blue flies are actually kinda good.
They all got consumed so fast just now.
Let's see here.
Oh, I can't see the map.
I don't think I even found a treasure room.
No, I must have since I found this, right?
Yeah.
We didn't find a shop, though, but does it matter with two coins?
No, we did find a shop.
Oh, so we're done.
Let's go.
Question mark versus dingle.
We got rainbow in here.
Good.
I have good range.
Oh, I thought he was gonna charge me.
Here he comes.
Nope.
What?
There he comes.
No!
The poop blocked me!
Insane.
Um, okay.
I mean, we already had so much range, man.
That feels...
Okay, so let's pay attention now.
Let's look at all our stats.
Snapshot the items.
Doo, doo, doo.
Got it.
Okay, now.
Nothing happened!
Amazing.
Poop.
And we move.
Actually, a decent start here with BB.
And we get to see the map now.
100% demon mode activated.
I cannot be taking damage like that willy-nilly.
Like that...
Every single heart I get is so incredibly important.
It's hard to describe, you know?
This character requires, like, insane game knowledge and movement.
You gotta be able to play this without taking any damage.
Wait, this is a...
Oh, wait a minute now.
That's a one.
Lost range, gained shot speed, and gained range.
That's actually good for me.
Oh, wait.
Oh, I changed my items!
Okay.
Torn photo.
Host hat.
Places a host on Isaac's head, which makes Isaac immune to explosion damage.
Ciiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiick.
Dude,
Spider-Bud...
Okay, man, I'm... I'm in.
I'm in.
I love that.
I wasn't married to my last items anyway.
This is cool.
Look at all my spiders!
Ah, well.
Can't win them all now.
Actually, I gotta go south.
We gotta still focus though.
Huge focus now.
Also, I need to write that down, by the way.
We gotta write the dice down.
So 1 and 6 do the same thing, it seems.
Let me write it down.
Wait.
Where's my window?
There it is.
Let's make a dice room.
Oh, we already have some.
1, reroll all items.
Actually, yeah, it doesn't affect my stats.
It just rerolled the items and that affected my stats in turn, right?
That's what happened there.
Okay.
A new item!
A little girdy.
A gird of your own.
Huh?
Charges up as Isaac continuously fires tears.
On release, launches itself across the room, bouncing around and dealing contact damage.
Oh, that's a long charge.
Let's see here.
Oh!
I wonder if I can charge that between rooms.
Wait.
Oh my god!
Charge it up.
Okay.
Let me see.
It does persist between rooms.
That's huge.
Oh my god, it's so good!
Also, I'm immune to those falling from the top.
Look at this.
Huge!
We need to lock in now.
This is a fantastic run so far.
Oh, I didn't charge.
I didn't pre-charge.
I fucked up on that.
Hahaha!
Dude, getting into a small enclosed area like that would actually be kind of dope.
Grant's flight.
Oh, that's cute.
I was about to say cute and huge, and it became huge.
Look at my little girdy.
He's vibrating.
He can't hold it any longer.
He can't wait.
He cannot wait!
We're not going to release him yet, though.
We're going to hold on to him.
We're going to the shop first.
We need to hold that...
Poopin'!
Okay, I release you.
Mom's bracelet.
Grab and pick up a...
No, wait.
The one I have right now is pretty good, right?
Ten damage is not that much, though.
Let me just kill this effect spawn blue spiders.
You know, it's not exactly amazing.
I think I want this instead.
Press an attack button to throw a held object, smashing it.
Yeah, this is going to be more helpful in the long run, for sure.
Especially with tinted rocks and stuff, right?
May have to do a quick look at all the rooms again.
In case I miss something.
Also, this room.
I'm not going to risk standing on it again.
I don't know if it can work twice.
But I got some pretty good items here.
Um, can I pick up this?
No way.
Oh, that's cool.
Wait, we're gonna...
Oh, this is so much better than I thought.
Look at that!
Oh my god.
This is great.
Alright guys, this run is going to take a while, okay?
Bear with me.
Okay, maybe not all the rocks, but definitely the pots and the...
Can I pick up mushrooms?
Oh my goodness!
What about the logs?
No?
Can I break walls with it?
Probably not.
We're getting money out of it.
Uh...
Wait, I can charge him?
I can shoot him without full charge.
Oh!
Nice!
I don't have to charge him all the way.
That's good to know.
I guess it's just going to be less damage or less bounces.
More money.
Look at all that money I'm getting.
I can go back to the shop in a second here and actually just clear it out.
You know what?
Nah, too lazy.
Maybe in here.
Okay.
Um, do I want anything else from here?
I don't think so.
I'm good.
We're going to save the rest.
Here we go!
A Duke of Flies.
Dude, we're going to do this.
I do wonder, does it do a lot of damage?
I mean, it kills the little guys.
Okay, dude, I release you.
Go!
No!
Okay, he bounced a little bit.
Are you ready again?
Go!
Yeah, good job, buddy.
Go again, I choose you now!
That was not a good throw.
Okay, I mean, that's not a blue heart for me.
Don't mind if I do.
Let me have a look in here.
Ceremonial Ropes.
Three black hearts!
That's totally worth it!
That's a no-brainer!
Holy shit!
Ocular Rift is one blue.
Chance to fire tears to summon a rift where they land.
I mean, this is also worth it.
Dude, this was cool!
Good trades here!
Massive.
Alright, go.
Look, the clock is ahead of us.
I should have pre-charged the
rift.
Okay, hold on, I'm going to come back here.
I'm just going to charge my little guy.
I'm guessing I can't pick up the spiky ones.
Hey, mushrooms!
I can pick them up.
Yeah, why not?
I love the bracelet.
I want pills.
No pills.
We're going to charge up little Gertie.
I love him.
He's such a little cutie!
Look at him!
Look at that smile!
Look how excited he is!
Yes, you're so cool!
What a little guy.
I need to see here.
Chance increases with luck.
I also need to use it to actually pick up items.
Okay, charge him up.
Yeah, let's just avoid that.
Huh.
Wait!
Wait a minute.
Can I potentially?
Damn.
Okay.
Too bad.
We're not going to go in there yet.
Actually, why not?
Let's do it.
Let's frickin' do it.
We're going to charge up, I believe.
Peep!
Boom!
Oh no, I got hit.
Yeah, yeah.
He's getting sucked towards the hole.
Good.
Dodge it!
Oh, man!
Oi, oi, oi.
Oh god, no!
Man, I'm not doing a lot of damage here.
That was not a good fight for me.
Shit.
The Empress.
Oh, what is that one?
Teardrop charm?
Increases chance of luck based shot.
Oh, that's good for me!
Dude!
The rift!
Except...
hello?
Oh, it didn't feel like it was that much better.
Equivalent to plus four luck, though.
I mean, you would think that would have a huge effect on that.
We haven't found any shops or any item rooms.
Dude, I'm a big boy.
We got to get all the mushrooms.
Come on, pill me.
What?
Nothing, huh?
Oh, I can...
Oh, wait, they can't leave the island, right?
Sister Maggie.
Okay.
All right, welcome to the party.
Oh, wait, I need to...
Fine.
That's pre-charge.
Oh, that was beautiful.
Actually, art.
School bag.
More pills.
I'm getting all the pills this time.
Lock down.
Okay, that's fine.
That puts me at plus three luck.
Technically with my shots.
Well, we found what we need to find.
Let's move on.
It's still looking good.
Four hearts is solid.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Okay.
No.
Oh, God.
Yeah, I get sucked into the hole.
Oh, wait, I need to...
Thank you, Gertie.
That was pretty good.
That went so much better than I thought it would.
Oi!
That is a massive find.
Wow.
Thank the Lord I'm destroying all these mushrooms.
Huh?
Pretty happy I'm doing that.
Uh, yeah, get in here.
Wait, wait, let's see what this is.
Shit.
Let's not touch it.
Okay, I'm not gonna grab that.
Absolutely not.
Not even with a ten-foot pole would I touch that.
No, not this room!
We're gonna die.
Gertie!
Yeah, suck them over there, that's good.
Yes!
Oh, we're killing it.
How am I doing this?
I'm on another level right now.
That could easily have been half my HP gone.
Okay.
Pre-charge Gertie.
What a trajectory, though.
Beautiful.
I need one that makes me smaller, though.
I'm way too big.
We got a pre-charge.
Oh, yeah.
Wait, did those fliers get sucked into Black Hole or did they just die?
It kind of looked like they got sucked in.
Um...
Oh, yeah, homing.
Oh, that's actually pretty good as well.
Oh, that's massive!
Gertie, you're my hero!
Diffuses troll bombs and converts them into bomb pickups.
Ah, but that's a trinket, right?
I don't like that.
Yeah, it's a trinket.
Hold on, his name is Gertie, right?
Let me just confirm this.
Yeah, a little Gertie.
So we have Seraphim.
Familiar that fires slow homing.
Okay.
I'm getting a lot of familiars.
I'm making a whole army here.
Oh, yeah, it gets sucked in, nerds!
Dude, the Black Hole thing is massive.
It's so good.
Wish I would find tidbit rocks, though, now that I have the ability to just grab them.
Wait, do these Black Holes also damage enemies?
Rift lasts for two seconds, pulling pickups and enemies towards them and dealing...
Oh, nice!
That's even better than I thought it was.
Incredible.
I may re-roll here.
Be still, my beating heart.
You will be mine.
I'll be back for you.
Oh, we also have an eternal heart here!
I'll be back for you, too!
Nobody left behind.
Gertie is MVP.
I'm not even going to risk taking that coin.
Hold on a minute.
We're just going to go in.
I'm feeling it.
I'm feeling the AGI.
He about to die.
Shit.
It's good, though.
Thanks.
Let's see what we got here.
That's the false PhD, right?
No, that's the pact.
Two black hearts!
Yo, that's a great trade-off!
Hello?
I'll take that trade any other week.
Exchange two blue for two black?
Hello?
Obviously.
Obviously I'll do that.
But hold on, I'm not leaving yet.
Come on now, did you think I was going to leave?
Did you really think I was going to leave?
Come on now.
We have things to do.
We need money.
And we got to collect the eternal heart as well.
Ah, I should have picked it up.
Gertie, careful!
There's bombs.
Alrighty.
Ah, we could make our money in the arcade.
This could be it.
We can make the money multiply.
Do you believe?
Right, I believe in the chat, if you believe, that I can turn five or four coins into fifteen.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Nice.
Good start.
Not, not good.
Shit.
Come on now, please, be good to me.
Ooh, come on, come on, make that money multiply.
Alright, bombs, you know I'm going to use those to kill you, right?
That was a mistake, buddy.
You shouldn't have done that.
I'm going to release Gertie on you if you don't give me ten coins.
Shit.
Let's fucking go!
Where are the doubters at?
Spider-mod, I told you I'll be back for you, I'd leave no one behind.
I'm going to grab this as well, and I'll be on my way.
Actually, not yet, we're going to blow up the machines as well.
We're going to blow it up, baby.
Let's do this.
Guys, I'm going to turn one gold into ten.
Are you a believer, or are you a doubter?
Let's hear it.
One gold, baby.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Be good to me, be good to me.
Shit, but wait, we're not done, we're not done, because watch.
Shit, we're not done, we're not done.
Hold on.
There we go.
We got more money.
Here we go.
Yep, yep, yep.
Come on.
Not good, not good.
We need more of those fivers.
I will let Gertie loose on you, I'm telling you.
So that's how it is, huh?
I have a bomb here with your name on it.
Let's go.
All right then, you die.
Oh, we almost made it to ten, don't we imagine if that was two black coins?
Imagine, imagine.
All right, we're leaving now.
For real though, we're leaving now.
Now we're leaving.
Wait, I should have tried to pick up one of the machines with my bracelet.
Maybe I can do that.
Think about it.
Ah, I'll keep it in mind.
Okay, okay, here we go, here we go.
An extra heart for me, that's lovely.
Precharge, Gertie.
Oh, what's happening here?
I'll use a coin, why not, or a key.
Wait, I wonder if I can pick this up.
I can't, okay.
Can I break it with a rock?
No.
We gotta blow it up.
Fragment at cart, new floors will generate an additional secret room.
Oh wait, it replaces my...
Oh.
No, you know what, I preferred this.
It's helping me with the black holes, right?
That's what I need, man.
Or rifts, I mean.
Okay.
I should have precharged.
Wait, there's a treasure chest there.
Well, he's Gertie.
Oh, he's off to Narnia.
A black heart, huge.
I love the spider mount so much.
Screw, look how big I am!
Look how huge I am!
Red patch, chance to gain damage up for the current room each time I take damage, increases with luck.
Well, I have minus one luck, so I think that's a bad idea.
Yeah,
wake up, I dare you, I double dare you.
Ah, I'm too fast.
See ya.
What's that?
Infestation.
Spawn two to six blue flies whenever Isaac takes...
Taking damage on this character is a horrible idea, so...
But I mean, better than nothing, right?
Oh man, oh man, oh man, oh man.
Minus one luck, no thanks.
Ah, I shouldn't have attacked him.
Okay, okay, uhh, this way.
Precharge.
Oh no.
Let me pre-calculate this.
Fuck!
I got hit.
Almost perfect.
Oh no.
Jesus.
Yeah, suck that bomb over there, suck it over there.
We got a fight room?
I don't know if I want to do that, actually I do want to do that.
One chest.
With some money, okay.
Release guardie.
One black hole, steal your thing, man.
Hoi, yoi, yoi.
I have a feeling, guys, right here.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Huh?
Wait, do we ha- uh...
Is there a labyrinth active?
I think so.
Compost.
Duplicates each blue spider and fly Isaac currently has.
Destroys all pickups on the ground in the current room when picked up and grants one blue spider or fly for each one destroyed.
That doesn't sound like a good thing.
Don't like that.
Um...
This one maybe could give me a blue heart.
In fact, have I ever seen a blue heart out of those?
Maybe they don't exist in those.
Can I pick you up?
Whoa.
Jeezus.
I gotta charge, uh, girdie here.
Come on, buddy.
Kill him.
Oof.
Sick.
Oh, it's pill time.
Oh, fuck.
It's fine.
This was a horrible selection of pills.
That was absolutely terrible.
It is what it is, though.
Oh, no.
Okay, uh, here we go.
Release him.
Girdie is going crazy.
Girdie, I need you to charge.
Left now.
More pills.
Okay.
And this one?
Curse of the Lost?
What if we do it again?
Maybe that'll undo it, you know?
I don't know.
Spitballing here.
Come on, girdie.
I can't believe I walked into that!
It's going horribly, guys.
We're throwing it.
Girdie, I need you.
I need you at your best behavior.
Okay, pause time.
Here we go!
Mask of Infamy.
Oh.
Get the heart down.
Good.
Now we kill this guy.
Girdie, go!
No, he dodged it last minute.
And...
go!
Huge backstab from girdie.
Wonderful.
Tears and shot speed.
That's good, though.
I feel like my best bet right now is actually not so much healing from items.
Most items healing, I guess...
I would rather just get healing from, like, chests and stuff.
And blue flames, you know?
But items... all about damage.
It's an arms race right now.
This is how I'm looking at it.
Okay, let's go.
Now it's mom!
Time for mom.
Here we go.
Okay, it's just a simple room.
Oh, I almost walked into the fire.
Nice one, girdie.
Oh, beautiful.
Get those black holes going.
Oh, no, the laser!
It's scariest when you can't see them off-screen, you know?
When they do that.
What?
Twenty-five coins!
Damn!
All right.
I've never seen that.
That's amazing.
Oh, no.
Keep moving, keep moving.
We cannot get hit by this.
Okay, we did it.
Moms pearl, increase chance of finding soul hearts.
Oh, yes.
I think that may actually... Oh, is it worth it?
I'm not sure it is.
I think it may be worth it.
Oh, god.
Dodge it!
Oi, oi, oi!
Girdie, go!
Get that heart down.
Massive, massive.
Let me in.
Are we going to pull these out with black holes?
I barely shoot black holes now, though.
This is the problem.
Stabler, that's good.
More damage.
I don't need that bomb, whatever.
All right, girdie, you ready?
Go!
Nice.
Good charge.
Okay.
Treasure room.
What's that?
Sprinkler.
Stationary turret that fires shots in a rotating pattern.
No, thanks.
I don't like that at all.
Let's find the boss.
I am ready to fight right now.
They explode.
Careful.
Oh, we're rich.
Sponsor sack.
Coins have a 10% chance to be converted to a sack.
Other pickups have a 20% chance.
I mean, sure, why not?
Oh, my character is huge.
Massive character.
We're going to donate, I think.
Just get those monies in there.
Okay, the boss has got to be down here, right?
We're going to long range this.
Black holes are going to suck them in, deal damage.
It's going to be great.
Play mega safe.
Actually, the black hole, we're going to do this and pull it out with the black hole.
Can we...
It's getting sucked.
A little more.
Maybe if I hit it here.
There we go.
Look at it.
Nice.
That's huge.
Oh!
A door has opened.
Balls of steel, baby!
There's also another blue heart in here, it seems.
Unless it's just not updated.
Yeah, it wasn't updated.
Fuck, we missed the mom room then.
Dude, I deal good amounts of damage here.
This is good.
I've never found anything good under these skulls.
Maybe there isn't anything good.
But I'm going to keep trying.
Who knows what there will be, right?
Also, am I getting bigger and bigger?
I don't know why I'm getting so big.
Okay, charge up again.
Come on, Gertie.
We got to go.
Yes.
Oh, that is incredible.
There was nothing else I wanted to buy.
So, I think we're good.
Here we go.
You ready?
Mom time.
Look at that fat leg.
I'm going to destroy it.
Gertie, go!
Oh, shit.
I shouldn't stand close to the wall.
That was bad.
Yeah.
Okay, good enough.
Good enough.
I'm happy with that.
I'm happy.
Could have been done better, but, you know, it is what it is.
Let's have a look in here.
Dead cat.
Oh, actually, that could be good here.
That could actually be good here, because we're kind of close to the end.
Ooh, pentagram.
Definitely that one.
Increases devil, angel, room chance, and a bunch of damage.
Definitely taking that.
Oh, the problem with dead cat, though, is if I actually lose my HP, I'm going to get sent back to the front of the room.
And, oh, man.
Like, I'm going to have to redo the boss, you know?
No.
Nope.
Just keep doing what I'm doing, man.
Keep going.
We're doing great so far.
We also have 23 bombs.
If we find blue flames, oh, you best believe we're going to, we're going to freakin' destroy those.
How am I not taking damage?
What just happened?
How did I not get hit there?
What is going on?
That was fucking crazy!
Wow.
Mom, no, no, no, no, no, no, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom.
Not ready.
Okay, I'm ready.
Gertie, you glorious motherfucker, you come with me.
I think I know why I didn't get hit.
It's all my familiars blocking shots, probably.
Uh, this room is weird.
Okay.
Go this way.
Release them.
Okay.
Come on, Gertie.
Dude, the black hole rift thingy is incredible.
We're also going to find all the secrets, by the way, because we have so many bombs.
Oh, they got pulled into me!
I got to be careful of that.
Charge up, my friend.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Jesus.
I love the rift.
Hey, did we get anything?
No.
What a weird room.
Really?
I'm playing inverted space invaders.
It feels great.
Okay, surely here, though.
Yes!
Uh-oh.
Gertie, I choose you!
We need to find a use for these coins.
Do we have a suspicious rock?
No.
Wow.
Dude, the boss is here!
We go for it.
The Fallen.
Gertie, you're my man.
Let's do this.
Fuck, I got hit.
Book of Belial?
At this point, it may actually be better than what I have.
I'm going for that.
Oof.
Do I move on?
Hmm.
I have so many bombs, though.
I could find secrets, maybe.
Yes!
Wait, what happened?
Oh, I didn't use it.
Blueheart, yes, that's what I was hoping for.
Huge.
Let's make a bomb here.
Evil poop.
Come on, Gertie!
Oh, shit.
Go!
Gertie, are you ready?
I fucking got hit by that.
Oh, man, we got to find more hearts.
Come on.
Maybe if I destroy these?
No?
I'm scared of this room.
Fuck, let's just go, man.
Moving on!
I have lost faith in finding.
Stuff in here.
Phew.
Uh, yeah, leave that behind.
Here we go!
I got plenty bombs to destroy things, anyway.
Now it's time for It Lives.
Charge up Gertie here.
Oh, be still.
No, no, not that way, not that way.
This way, this way, come here, come here.
Get sucked this way, yes, yes.
No, no, no, no, not that, not that.
Can I see what that is over there?
Let me pull it this way first.
Yes, and now that it's there, we're going to pull it this way.
Come on.
No, no, no, come on.
Yes, yes.
Oh, shit, it's minus tiers, okay.
Huge, oh, eternal heart!
We're going to take that at the end.
Okay.
Oh, God.
This is a development, isn't it?
Gertie, go!
See you, nerd!
Holy...
Grant's flight for the room, that's pretty cool.
Better than amnesia.
What would you rather?
Be able to fly like a bird or have amnesia?
Oh, God, this is actually...
Kill him!
Nice.
Oh, wait, there's another path.
I'm being sucked this way!
Oh, I was walking that way.
This room is scaring me right now.
That's a lot of money.
Come here, buddy.
Okay, okay.
Gertie, I need you again.
You're my best friend, Gertie.
Here it is!
Let's do it!
Book of Belial.
We're gonna do Book of Belial and Hankman.
Gertie?
Are you ready, Gertie?
Go!
Fuck, yeah!
Wait, we still got projectiles?
Oh, I can't see what it is?
Ah!
We can't do it, then.
Oh, no, maybe I'll do it.
Maybe I'll fucking do it.
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, I'm tempted.
I'm tempted.
No.
Yes.
No!
If I do it, I'm gonna have half a blue heart.
I can't do it.
We gotta go.
I can't.
I can't do it.
I'm too much of a pussy.
To be fair, though, I think we're nearing the end of the run here.
This is...
We don't have a lot of HP, is what I'm saying here.
This is not good.
Oh, fuck.
Not this.
Wait, I need to think.
I need to think.
So, he shoots and then I go left?
No!
Thank God I didn't take that item.
I would have been dead now.
Oh, ho, ho, ho.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Come on, please.
Yes!
Come on.
Can I get over there?
Somehow.
Can I be smart about... what if I blow this rock up?
Can I...
What the heck, man?
I fly!
I fly.
Oh, yes.
Sure.
Why not?
Okay, here we go.
We're going left.
Gertie, you are my favorite person in the entire world.
I love you.
Let's go north.
Oh, no.
We're in deep shit here.
We're in deep shit.
Maybe.
It's okay, it's okay.
Let me inspect these rocks.
Inspect it, let's go.
Gertie, let's see you go crazy.
I want to see the best Gertie-ness out of you.
Come on.
What's that?
I don't like what I'm seeing.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
Calm down, Gertie.
We're alive, we're alive.
Kill him.
Gertie, you are the man.
Save me from this torment.
Phew.
Here, watch.
Fuck, I'm good.
Evil fires!
Kill him.
Extinguish.
Oh.
Jesus.
Yeah!
Okay, we can also move from this room, so we're going to do this, maybe?
No, maybe here?
Okay, maybe here?
Wait, the pause is here!
Should we cover it?
Here we go!
Belial and death!
Belial and death, are you ready?
By the powers of the heavens, grant me strength.
For I'm about to face myself.
Belial!
Go, Gertie!
Gertie, Gertie!
I can't see shit.
I got hit.
Gertie, go!
I need you to go, Gertie.
Come on.
You're on, Gertie.
I need your prowess right now.
Yeah!
What do you say to that?
Who's the man?
Who's the fucking man?
It's just the same cutscene.
What?
I was expecting something crazy.
The guy was called Question Mark, Question Mark, Question Mark.
I thought for sure we would get something from this.
Something... the Polaroid has appeared?
Brains.
You unlocked Pong.
What about Ping, though?
Look at that!
It's an Italian!
I knew it from the start!
Look at it!
I fucking knew it!
That explains everything.
Unbelievable.
He has headphones on.
Dude.
What a run.
Hold on a minute.
Secrets.
I need to see this again.
Oh no, it's not gonna show me in the frickin' latest?
Really?
Something about Isaac.
Hold on.
The D6?
Huh?
Okay.
Did we unlock a new character by doing this?
We have 10 Eden tokens?
Mmm...
wait.
I was kind of hoping that we would also get a name for this guy now that we did it, you know?
I'm curious about that, though.
Oh, wait a minute.
Hey, look!
We got... oh, wait!
Maybe it means we beat the heart and we beat the church level, you know, because of the cross.
I think that's what that means.
Ah, and this means we beat the upside-down cross, which is hell.
Right?
We even go to heaven or we go to hell?
So that means we beat Satan on Samson.
I don't remember if we did, but I think we did.
Wait, we got a star on Lazarus?
What does that mean?
Hold on, what did we do on Lazarus?
That was crazy.
Did we do anything there?
It could have been the one thing where we beat all the, like, 15 waves or something.
I think that may have been on Lazarus.
Because that was a one-time thing that happened.
That was like a special thing, you know?
Cain, we got those two.
Greed, for sure.
But wait, that means Eulith should have it too, right?
Yep.
Okay, everything's making sense.
And that's it, ladies and gentlemen.
We made it.
What a set of runs today.
What do you say to that, huh?
Come on now.
That was badass.
What a banger of a last... Like, I was on the edge of my seat the entire time.
And my gambling addiction paid off hugely.
Wasn't that the craziest shit ever?
I feel like that run was even better than the run from last stream where I broke everything.
You played really well today?
Thank you, thank you.
I'm bowing in real life, you can't see it, but I'm doing the fancy bow.
I think I did well.
I'm also proud of myself today.
This is so cool.
Dude, I thought I was addicted to this game.
I'm even more addicted now.
I want to just keep going, but I gotta, you know, I gotta go.
I gotta go.
But not yet.
I kind of just want to wallow in the success here and absorb all your compliments right now.
This game is worse than crack.
You know what we should do?
All the people addicted to crack just hand out cheap laptops with a Binding of Isaac installed.
That'll replace their addiction fast.
It'll be healthy and, you know, they'll learn to use computers.
Everyone gets really smart.
Because everyone knows being good at Binding of Isaac makes you very smart, you know?
D6 is massive, you should try it.
I mean, I expect it's gonna be just like the D6 room.
But as an active, which sounds fucking crazy.
I don't know.
Don't confirm or deny that.
I'm just thinking out loud, right?
But, yeah.
Of course I'm gonna play Isaac next stream.
I gotta see what that is all about.
If the random roll of character grants me Isaac.
Listen, I don't have choice in this.
That is up to chance.
I just roll the dice and we see what we get.
Look, look at it this way.
If we didn't roll the dice today, we wouldn't have gotten these amazing runs.
I probably would have been raging with Eulith still.
Think about that.
I would have been crying a river and I would be bathing in it as Eulith.
Eight of Seysela runs in a row.
I don't mind.
Let's go.
I'm fucking ready.
The gambling luck was crazy.
Nah, it's skill.
It's skill, bro.
There's no luck in there.
I told you I was gonna... I told you I was gonna get 15 coins.
And what did I get?
15 coins.
Random BB drop was also... wait, BB drop?
Random BB drop.
Are you talking about blue boy?
Oh, yeah, okay, okay.
Yeah, it was insane.
Beyond birthday.
Next level birthday.
BB from Silksong.
Yeah, that's what I think of.
And I also think of BB from Death Stranding.
Gertie actually did like 10 damage per room.
Wait, how do you know?
Do you have like statistics?
Did you do some kind of statistics on that or...?
Oh, spider mod.
Ah, oh, I see.
I mean, the thing is though, think of it like this.
Gertie was there for mental and moral support.
He was my friend through that last run.
I wouldn't have made it without him.
It doesn't matter how much damage he did.
He was there to support me.
He was there to push back the enemies and give me, you know, the confidence that I needed.
Gertie is the man.
Gertie was tired at the end.
Yes, Gertie definitely deserves a well-deserved rest here.
He's gonna chillax with some pancakes and some chocolate milk.
I'm gonna put on his favorite show.
Put him under the covers and he's gonna, you know, sit there with his laptop.
It's gonna be great.
Gertie carry.
Indeed, I didn't do nothing.
It was all Gertie.
Little Gertie.
If you want to check out the unlocks, you can just do it with steam achievements.
Oh, good point.
Actually, let me check that now.
That's actually a great point.
Pong was a challenge.
The Polaroid.
Unlock the new item.
Dead baby.
Unlock the new co-player baby.
Brains.
That doesn't say anything.
The D6.
Flooded caves.
Alt-stage to the caves.
And then we have Eve's bird foot.
Golden razor.
Oh, obtain 99 pennies, then spend every single one of them.
Of course I would do that.
Nice.
I like spending the money in this game.
99 is not enough.
I could go for 200.
No problem.
Yeah, they're burning a hole in my pants pocket.
Wait, did I have money equals power in this run right now, or are we talking about an earlier one on Doko?
Dude, you know what?
You are so right, Yujuri.
I was so extremely invested in it.
It was just like a movie.
I kind of want to make like a cinematic edit of that run with like music and cuts and make it like...
Should I fucking do it?
I'm going to put it on YouTube.
We're going to make a crazy cinematic like live action remake.
What's that going to look like?
Who's going to star as Gertie?
That's what I want to know.
Who's going to be Gertie in that one?
Paint yourself blue to play.
Yeah, I guess I could do that.
Jack Black.
I'm just imagining him rolled up as a tiny fetus.
You know, rolling around the room, bouncing off the walls.
Making Jack Black noises.
Timothy Chalamet.
I feel like he's too handsome to be Gertie.
Not that Gertie is ugly.
He's just definitely not like Timothy Chalamet levels.
You know?
DeVito is perfect, actually.
Danny DeVito?
Yes.
Beautiful.
What's up, Geyer Bowser?
1400 hours in Isaac.
Damn.
How many do I have now?
Let's see.
I have 68.6 hours in Isaac.
No, yeah.
According to Steam.
But that's also a bit of idling in the menu.
Sometimes forgetting to close the game, so I don't know how precise that is.
I guess you can compare it with my streams, you know, and see if there's any leftovers that's probably just idling.
That's a good amount?
Yeah.
Oh yeah, close to 69.
Shit.
And how many achievements?
Wait.
19%.
Jesus Christ.
Wait, how many?
There's 641 achievements in this game.
What the fuck?
All right.
Wow.
I'm 60% done.
Nice.
You're shooting down with the game then.
Do you believe now when we say you're 20% in there?
No.
I'm 19% in there.
Duh.
Guys, I'm out of here.
This was an excellent surprise fun stream here.
I love this game.
I am totally addicted to Isaac, and I'm not afraid to admit it.
It's the truth.
It is.
You will see more Isaac.
I'll see you around.